<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quotidian Quest</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://quotidianquest.com/</id><updated>2016-08-03T00:08:15-07:00</updated><entry><title>Diagrams in the post</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2016/08/diagrams-in-the-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-08-03T00:08:15-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2016-08-03:2016/08/diagrams-in-the-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I thought I would switch gears for a second and see if I could get pelican to make certain diagrams for my blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Sample sequence diagram" classes="sequence" src="http://quotidianquest.com/images/17033b95.svg" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope that works.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="pelican"></category><category term="diagrams"></category><category term="plantuml"></category></entry><entry><title>Opening up on the internet</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2016/07/opening-up-on-the-internet.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-07-20T13:38:12-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2016-07-20:2016/07/opening-up-on-the-internet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently spent some time chatting on the internet about some of the problems that I've been having with getting things done since my "fun-employment" the last couple of months. It is very hard for me, because I've been told that I'm smart and have potential all of my life and here I am in my mid 30's and there aren't a line of people knocking on my door to give me money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I did this, I felt good. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt like I wasn't just someone lost in the wind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to stay involved with the community and make it my touch stone as I work towards finding more work.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="blog"></category><category term="slack"></category></entry><entry><title>Why not me?</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2016/06/why-not-me.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-06-26T15:29:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2016-06-26:2016/06/why-not-me.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We don't get a chance to start our lives over again. Even if we could, there is no garuntee that what we do will be better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we can do is move on and change ourselves even by a little to make our lives better. I'm going to do that publicly and you are more than welcome to keep reading along. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="starting over"></category><category term="change"></category></entry><entry><title>Where have I been?</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2016/06/where-have-i-been.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-06-21T20:54:03-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2016-06-21:2016/06/where-have-i-been.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ok, it is time to get back into writing on my blog. I think I'm going to track my progress with learning swift 3 and my other tutorials that I come across.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Further thoughts on text expander</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2016/04/further-thoughts-on-text-expander.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-05-14T22:52:52-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2016-04-11:2016/04/further-thoughts-on-text-expander.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, &lt;a href="http://quotidianquest.com/2016/04/my-thoughts-on-text-expander.html"&gt;I posted about my thoughts on Text Expander&lt;/a&gt; after they announced that they were going to be moving to a subscription. And I got some feedback regarding what I wrote. I've pasted it below because I honestly don't get any feed back regarding any of my writing&lt;label for="feedback" class="margin-toggle sidenote-number"&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type="checkbox" id="feedback" class="margin-toggle" /&gt;&lt;span class="sidenote"&gt;Most likely because I do not have comments on the site&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I completely agree that they have kind of boxed themselves out of the "casual user" market and are now more focused on "power users" or those that are using this tool on multiple devices (like me)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think your point is very well written, but would love to see more information about the alternative (AutoHotKey) that you have selected. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps it would be helpful to mention a couple of things (If any) that could make textexpander that tool for you again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great job though. You can definitely tell that you care about the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's just they don't fit in your system anymore (which happens)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like feedback. At this point, good or bad I'm happy with the fact that someone else is reading and it gives me some motivation to make the writing better. In this case, I'd like to further expand on the last two points in the reverse order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;3. How to make the tool more helpful for me&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is actually a something that needs to happen on my end&lt;label for="disservice" class="margin-toggle sidenote-number"&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type="checkbox" id="disservice" class="margin-toggle" /&gt;&lt;span class="sidenote"&gt;To be fair, the application tries its best to help me be as productive as possible.&lt;/span&gt;.  The people at smile give you a number of examples that you can use right away to save you time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;When I was making this post, I added one more. If anything knowing that I might have to give the application up has sparked new interest in using it. Plus all the the writing that I've been doing.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;img src="../../images/my_textexpander_setup_2016-04.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application does help in one major way everyday (when I do use it). Most mornings, I do use it to create my grateful journal template&lt;sup id="fnref:affirmation"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:affirmation" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  Here is a brief example of the template that I use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;# Things I&amp;#39;m Grateful for #
+ 

# Things I&amp;#39;m Excited about #
+ 

# One Thing I&amp;#39;d like to focus on #
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;By default, the application will monitor what you type and suggest even more snippets that you can add to your collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;I was kind of shocked by some of the things that I write multiple times and it has the possibility of helping me change some habits.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;img src="../../images/my_textexpander_suggestions.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe, I shouldn't have freaked out when I saw this feature pop up and you can always change the way it works in the preference because it could have been helpful. But it seemed creepy and annoying. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Part of me was getting annoyed with all the notifications on what I could use as a snippet.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;img src="../../images/my_textexpander_preferences_2016-04.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're feeling adventurous you can even go to the website of one of my heroes &lt;a href="http://brettterpstra.com/"&gt;Brett Terpstra&lt;/a&gt; and check out his page of &lt;a href="http://brettterpstra.com/projects/te-tools/"&gt;text expander tools&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all this, I still find that I wasn't using it to the fullest&lt;label for="text_expander_usage" class="margin-toggle"&gt;&amp;#8853;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type="checkbox" id="text_expander_usage" class="margin-toggle" /&gt;&lt;span class="marginnote"&gt;&lt;img class="fullwidth" src="../../images/my_textexpander_usage.png" alt="This was my last usage stat. Take it with a *HUGE* grain of salt because I only have it on my laptop and I do frequent re-installs"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This was my last usage stat. Take it with a &lt;em&gt;HUGE&lt;/em&gt; grain of salt because I only have it on my laptop and I do frequent re-installs&lt;/span&gt;. Ultimately, we all have to balance what we want versus what we need the money to go to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2. AutoHotKey&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this topic, I don't have much to say because I no longer have a windows machine to use on a day to day basis. The great thing about this tool was that I was using it to now only fire off extensions but to launch applications and replicate user interactions for testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would often use a keyboard short cut to launch the vnc client because the laptop that was given to employees to use might not be that powerful or we wanted to run a test on another machine that had a faster connection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For user interactions, I created a script that would type in the keyboard shortcut that would make windows rotate the screen or do a series of mouse clicks to reproduce... something...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1. Updated...&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was writing this, Smile reduced the price to $20 a year for the software. Which changes the deal significantly. Now I have to think about what the software is going to do for me going forward. Is this going to save me time in the future? Will I save more time than the time that I used writing about it here? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:affirmation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's an exercise that I do in the morning when I feel a little overwhelmed with life. I'm making it a habit and automating the prompt helps. Although, I do use &lt;a href="https://www.keyboardmaestro.com"&gt;Keyboard Meastro&lt;/a&gt; to do something similar.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:affirmation" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="text expander"></category><category term="response"></category></entry><entry><title>My thoughts on Text Expander</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2016/04/my-thoughts-on-text-expander.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-04-10T20:39:34-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2016-04-10:2016/04/my-thoughts-on-text-expander.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://textexpander.com"&gt;TextExpander&lt;/a&gt; is a tool that I forget that I have. Actually, TextExpander is a tool that I forget to use. In the last couple of years, I've moved to a workflow that really isn't working for me day to day. I have a laptop, an imac, a couple ipads and all the work computers&lt;sup id="fnref:windows"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:windows" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that have been supplied for me to use in the last couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, the people at Smile software have switch the software to be a subscription model. On one hand, I understand that some companies need to do this to keep their businesses afloat; the monthly revenue is better to budget against versus someone purchasing the software every major release (maybe). On the other hand, this means that as a user I don't "own" the software; I'm leasing&lt;label for="leasing" class="margin-toggle"&gt;&amp;#8853;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type="checkbox" id="leasing" class="margin-toggle" /&gt;&lt;span class="marginnote"&gt;It seems to be the trend nowadays that people pay a fee to use things from homes(rent), cars and music. I do not have a problem with it, but it seems like a lot of money is going to things that we will not be able to get some equity back from.&lt;/span&gt; it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I can see why they would do something like that. The company specializes in tools like this and pdfpen and I like the fact that they sponsor a lot of podcasts that I listen to. I wish them well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I don't think I'll be joining them on this experiment. I'm not a power user of the software. Because of the way that I've been living my technical life, I haven't seen myself repeating a lot of text. You can probably see the result of this in the fact that I don't post that often. The header for this posting is stored as a text expander snippet but I find myself having to look it up in order to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish them luck and I'm happy to use my current version until it stops working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:windows"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On windows, I've switched to using &lt;a href="https://www.autohotkey.com"&gt;AutoHotKey&lt;/a&gt; because I can use text expansion as well as actions such as prepping an email to my wife so I can send her a message telling her that I love her.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:windows" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="text expander"></category></entry><entry><title>Starting with Hazel</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2016/03/starting-with-hazel.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-03-22T10:41:11-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2016-03-22:2016/03/starting-with-hazel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Initial Creation of Hazel rule" src="../../images/initial_hazel.png" /&gt; 
I write all of my blog post in markdown and store them in a folder in dropbox. From there, I use pelican to turn the files into a webpage.  The steps would be...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Byword or &lt;a href="http://multimarkdown.com/index.html"&gt;MultiMarkdown Composer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write the post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember the textexpander snippet that I created for post headers because I don't post as often as I used to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save the file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the file to location where I have pelican looking&lt;sup id="fnref:publish"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:publish" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate the site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish the site by copying the generated file to the proper git repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push the repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check that all the links work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I decided that I've already bought tons of productivity tools and should use them for what they are for. I had a couple workflows in the past but not saving them while I switch between betas causes the system to falter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not the complicated rule set, but it certainly a start and makes me happy that I'm actual using the things that I've bought. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Completed rule set for moving my posts to get processed" src="../../images/sorting_cloning_with_hazel.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:publish"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my fault for not setting up pelican to auto publish. I just want to make sure that everything works locally before I send it out to my millions of fans.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:publish" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Tufte margin figure and column images</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2016/03/tufte-margin-figure-and-column-images.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-03-16T11:02:52-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2016-03-16:2016/03/tufte-margin-figure-and-column-images.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are a couple things that I still have to finish for the website theme plugin. They are margin images and images in the main column. It should be to hard and in fact this post that you are reading is an example of me using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, I'm going to put a margin image here on the side followed by a small table of what I had for breakfast the last three days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for="margin-figure-id" class="margin-toggle"&gt;&amp;#8853;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type="checkbox" id="margin-figure-id" class="margin-toggle" /&gt;&lt;span class="marginnote"&gt;&lt;img class="fullwidth" src="../../images/small_me.jpg" alt="This is guy keeps getting better!"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is guy keeps getting better!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align="left"&gt;Day of week&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align="left"&gt;Breakfast&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;Sunday&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;Eggs and fruit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;Monday&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;Protein Shake&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;Tuesday&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;Leftover serial&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, wasn't that amazing&lt;label for="reflection" class="margin-toggle"&gt;&amp;#8853;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type="checkbox" id="reflection" class="margin-toggle" /&gt;&lt;span class="marginnote"&gt;Although this all looks nice, I think this might be the last update to the code for a while.&lt;/span&gt;
. Now that we got that working we can get the column images working too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to follow up with the column image. I hope that it looks cool in your browser of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;This example was lefted directly from the Tufte website. I hope that it works.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;img src="../../images/napoleons-march.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, until next time!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Finished open graph</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2016/03/finished-open-graph.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-03-06T14:25:50-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2016-03-06:2016/03/finished-open-graph.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So,  I spent about 3 hours working on getting Open Graph tags to work in the theme that I created. I've got mixed feeling about it because I started off by adding the tags to the base html template using an if statement and it seemed a little clunky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;OPEN_GRAPH&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;&amp;lt;meta property=&amp;quot;og:title&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;SITENAME&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;&amp;lt;meta property=&amp;quot;og:type&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;website&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;&amp;lt;meta property=&amp;quot;og:description&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;SITE_DESCRIPTION&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;&amp;lt;meta property=&amp;quot;og:url&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;SITE_URL&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;endif&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;OPEN_GRAPH&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cp"&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This worked for the site in general but doesn't translate to all the articles and this caused me to go into a some what deep dive into how Pelican and Jinja parses blocks and if statements. I started off with putting all the tags into the base and then doing individual changes to tags that need to be changed for. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BAH!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, took a step back and looked into what plugins were already available. And there is was! &lt;a href="https://github.com/whiskyechobravo/pelican-open_graph"&gt;Pelican-open_graph&lt;/a&gt;! I was home free! Or so I thought, until I tried to use it. The plugin has three problems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It doesn't  account for when someone does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have a modified date on their articles.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AntoineVe/pelican-open_graph"&gt;Luckily, someone had put a solution up&lt;/a&gt;. The change was forked about 7 months ago today and it looks like whoever created the open graph plugin has taken a break to work on other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It's a year old and hasn't made the changes for pelican regarding summaries of articles.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I had to do some debugging to find out that the code needed to be changed in the following way&lt;sup id="fnref:payitforward"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:payitforward" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ogtags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;og:description&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;instance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;metadata&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;og_description&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                                                           &lt;span class="n"&gt;instance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;metadata&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;summary&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                                                                                 &lt;span class="n"&gt;instance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;summary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;It also assumed that every article has some kind of tag.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've decided to just punt this problem and add the tags to the 6 articles that don't have them, but than I took a second look at the problem because the perfectionist in me doesn't like to leave problems unsolved and I didn't want to track down what the particular articles were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I just wrapped the code in a try block to make sure that I got this particular exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;try&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;tag&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;instance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;tags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="n"&gt;ogtags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;article:tag&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;tag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;except&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ne"&gt;AttributeError&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="n"&gt;ogtags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;article:tag&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;untagged&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I got to learn a little bit more about using pelican and knocked off a major milestone on getting this blog to where I'd like it to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:payitforward"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've got to branch and push this fix. I don't know how many other people are using pelican or this plugin but if I can save them or future me some time...&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:payitforward" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="blog"></category><category term="open graph"></category></entry><entry><title>A small return</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2016/02/a-small-return.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-02-07T20:33:36-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2016-02-07:2016/02/a-small-return.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently pushed the button to update my site and push my new theme to the world. It felt good to get it out there because it has been dormant for years now and I had thought about shutting it down sometimes. During the time that I had &lt;em&gt;NOT&lt;/em&gt; updated, I had switched jobs and kind of doubted everything I was working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a lot of ways, the doubt in my own abilities was part of the reason that it took so long to update because I just didn't think that it was good enough. In my mind, I thought "If it's not perfect than I won't show anything at all".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the wrong way of thinking about it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's almost childish in a way and reminds me of how I'd refuse to write the steps when I was doing my math homework&lt;sup id="fnref:homework"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:homework" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;So now what?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I've got a new redesign that loads really fast and looks pretty cool. The next steps outside of the technical details that I put in my previous post is to find my direction of the site again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, I'm using &lt;a href="https://dayone.me"&gt;Day One&lt;/a&gt; for my journal entries and although this is my personal site I don't think I'll be putting entries from there here (more likely is that this entry will be an entry).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I'll probably put links to things that are really cool or some tutorials that I've been thinking about making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll have to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:homework"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was something that a couple of high school friends would do. We thought it was cool to get the answer completely in our head without writing all the steps of logic down on paper. It was stupid because the teacher would give you partial credit if you showed your work. &amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:homework" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Publishing incompletes</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2016/02/publishing-incompletes.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-02-02T06:06:15-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2016-02-02:2016/02/publishing-incompletes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, I've decided that I was going to push my website out to the masses before the end of the week. This is a personal blog and just because it isn't &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; it is something that I created and I want to take pride in the fact that I'm willing to get out there and work on something and make it better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the things that I'd like to work on will be the handling of navigation at the top and figuring out how to get the tufte style to work properly with pelican. I attempted to get everything working with a liquid tag but the parser doesn't work well with blocklevel tags and wraps it in &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; so the expected css doesn't apply properly. This only applies to fullwidth figures but I'd like it all to be uniform.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="misc"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Researching without wifi</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2015/12/researching-without-wifi.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-12-13T09:56:05-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2015-12-13:2015/12/researching-without-wifi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The power went out this morning and left the house in darkness except for my laptop. I took this time to get some work done with my plugin for &lt;a href="http://www.getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; but I found myself at a stand still because I wanted to get some information on how regular expressions parse results into a dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the internet not working, I decided that I'd try seeing what is available with the REPL in python and I found it to be fairly helpful in the fact that I had access to the documentation in the same interface as the code that I was writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case, I wanted to find out what methods are part of the match class. Sure, I ran into a minor bump of not knowing how to get help to show me the documentation of match directory, but I quickly got around that by run help on the match object that I created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Exploring python in the terminal" src="../../images/Exploring_Python_in_terminal.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, this gives me a little more confidence in myself that I can find things out on my own without having to turn to the internet and finding myself getting side tracked by all the destractions that someone can find. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="terminal"></category></entry><entry><title>Testing the plugins</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2015/12/testing-the-plugins.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-12-07T21:27:48-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2015-12-07:2015/12/testing-the-plugins.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is just a quick little page that will have some examples of notes used in the Tufte style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I hope this&lt;label for="Basic-Marginnote" class="margin-toggle"&gt;&amp;#8853;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type="checkbox" id="Basic-Marginnote" class="margin-toggle" /&gt;&lt;span class="marginnote"&gt;Margin notes can be used for more than just putting information about a particular article.&lt;/span&gt; works or I'm going to have to work on it some more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I've got to work on sidenotes as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something else that I want to work on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/ihnatko.jpg" alt="hey" title="hey"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorem Ipsum is simply dummy text of the printing and typesetting industry. Lorem Ipsum has been the industry's standard dummy text ever since the 1500s, when an unknown printer took a galley of type and scrambled it to make a type specimen book. It has survived not only five centuries, but also the leap into electronic typesetting, remaining essentially unchanged. It was popularised in the 1960s with the release of Letraset sheets containing Lorem Ipsum passages, and more recently with desktop publishing software like Aldus PageMaker including versions of Lorem Ipsum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;layoffs Instagram Paul Steiger privacy commons-based peer production Arianna mathewi but what's the business model Tim Carmody metered model Wikipedia, hashtag Snarkmarket digital first hot news doctrine CPC learnings Free Darko Colbert bump.&lt;label for="sidenote-id" class="margin-toggle sidenote-number"&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type="checkbox" id="sidenote-id" class="margin-toggle" /&gt;&lt;span class="sidenote"&gt;This is a random sidenote&lt;/span&gt; recontextualize free as in beer privacy A.J. Liebling RSS Free Darko dying Mozilla recontextualize, Article Skimmer information wants to be free Colbert bump privacy production of innocence privacy metered model, #twittermakesyoustupid Steve Jobs copyboy Demand Media WordPress Fuego West Seattle Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="tufte"></category></entry><entry><title>Silver Bullets &amp; Pedestals</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2015/10/silver-bullets-pedestals.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-10-23T23:27:41-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2015-10-23:2015/10/silver-bullets-pedestals.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I follow a &lt;a href="http://brettterpstra.com"&gt;number&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="http://www.macdrifter.com"&gt;nerdy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://macsparky.com"&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; on the internet. In my mind I put them on pedestals and marvel at how they make things look so easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to buy all the tools to emulate them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking for that one silver bullet that will make it click for me as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align="left"&gt;Application&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align="left"&gt;Results thus far&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;TextExpander&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;Saved .99 hours&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;Keyboard Maestro&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;36 Hours&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;&lt;a href="http://brettterpstra.com/2013/01/26/a-guided-tour-of-my-hyper-key-shortcuts/"&gt;Hyper Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;Works on my laptop but had trouble with the keyboard I was using at the time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</summary><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Why Keep My Site?</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2014/04/why-keep-my-site.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-15T21:59:41-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2014-04-15:2014/04/why-keep-my-site.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My personal blog hasn't been changed in over a year. I've been waiting for that perfect moment when it would be ready for the world. Unfortunately, it's been stifled because of my own drive for it to be perfect before it sees the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I don't think anyone reads it and it's not going to get better unless I put some time into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before I put any more effort into it, I want to take some time and write about why I should keep it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Web Technology is cool&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like working on the web. Until this point, I never thought that I'd be considering a career where I'd be working on the web, but I've spent a lot of my life working or playing with something that is some how web related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Play around with different tech&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bare minimum, having a website allows you to play around with what can happen on the inter-webs and make that part of what people find when they google, bing or duck-duck-go your name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;My Part of the web&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, having your own website is about control. I control the content and what it looks like and if I choose. I can shut it down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vanity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Provide a Place to Share My Opinion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't say much, but I know that this is the perfect platform because I choose to write here and I don't have to worry too much about saying "the wrong thing."&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Wednesday Challenge: Milk</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2013/11/wednesday-challenge-milk.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-11-25T11:16:08-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2013-11-20:2013/11/wednesday-challenge-milk.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;"Andrew will be coming by tomorrow", PaPa says excitedly. "He should be here now instead of running around with those hoodlums."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncle Andrew has been dead for years...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking in to PaPa's milky eyes, I don't have it in me to tell him again tonight.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="milk"></category></entry><entry><title>Figure testing</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2013/10/figure-testing.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-30T12:29:59-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2013-10-30:2013/10/figure-testing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm just writing this to make it place the file in the write spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Simple Picture of me" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7420/10482027083_3f98e13418.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that this works properly.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="html"></category></entry><entry><title>Mussing about christian music</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2013/10/mussing-about-christian-music.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-30T10:00:32-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2013-10-30:2013/10/mussing-about-christian-music.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite things about Christian music is that it is encouraging with a lot of popular music, you only hear about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;heartbreak&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;drugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I was listening and I head a song that asked a simple question&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you happy where your life is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't hear that question on other stations.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Shadowslayer: Dawn of the Lightforge</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2013/10/shadowslayer-dawn-of-the-lightforge.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-15T12:05:50-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2013-10-15:2013/10/shadowslayer-dawn-of-the-lightforge.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I saw this in the app store, I thought this was an alright game. It had a fairly high rating, but I think that the developers must have gamed the rating system because anyone who has gotten passed the initial tutorial would be quickly bored by the tedious amount of grinding and the amount of in-app purchases that you get hammered with every time you want to do something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game has two different kinds of currency: One that proves pointless after 20 minutes and a true currency that you can only get by paying with real money. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen, if you're looking for a game that you only play once a day without paying $2-3, then this is it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="games"></category></entry><entry><title>An accomplishment</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2013/10/an-accomplishment.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-13T22:50:29-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2013-10-13:2013/10/an-accomplishment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've had a little idea going on in the back of my head for the last couple of months about a simple application that would pop up after a given keyboard shortcut. It's a simple idea and never got around to doing it because I didn't sit down and do it. Even on the days, where I thought "Hey,If I had an easy way to keep track of all the good things that I've done, I'd feel better about myself". Normally, I just look at the todo item that I had in OmniFocus and just push it back a couple days or weeks because of priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But today, I sat down and decided that if I wanted to really follow my own words about controlling my life I've got to make good on the commitments that I make to myself big or small. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I sat down behind my laptop opened up my AppleScript 1-2-3&lt;sup id="fnref:unused"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:unused" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and started searching the internet after not seeing a solution to my problems on the first page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;set&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;theSumm&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;text returned&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;display dialog&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Latest Accomplishment&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;buttons&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;OK&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;default&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;answer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;A step forward&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;default&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;button&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;OK&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;tell&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;application&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Calendar&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nb"&gt;make&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;todo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;at&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;todos&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;calendar&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Accomplishments&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;properties&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;summary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;theSumm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;completion&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;current date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;tell&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;At first, I was just going to put this in a script file and then run it from a service, but I decided that the easiest way of doing this was to use &lt;a href="http://www.keyboardmaestro.com/main/" title="An app that I've been using more and more to get things moving quickly."&gt;Keyboard Maestro&lt;/a&gt;. It was really cool that I got to move the entire script into the application so I didn't have to move between the different applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mandaris/10540756656/" title="A screenshot of my first keyboard maestro attempt to make a short cut to log my accomplishments"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3783/10540756656_0d7bd92af3.jpg" width="427" height="500" alt="A copy of my first keyboard maestro attempt to make a short cut to log my accomplishments"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I had originally envisioned, but I started to think about the limitations of keeping all of this in reminders. All the applications that use the system built &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/osx/apps/#reminders" title="The default todo application on Mac OSX"&gt;task management tools&lt;/a&gt; have a focus on what needs to be done and if I want to have way to look at this stuff quickly and I wasn't sure how to look at accomplishments that were marked as completed a month ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a look at what I was doing on a daily basis and saw that I've been doing more and more journaling using &lt;a href="http://dayoneapp.com" title="Day One is a great simple application that allows you to have a journal that syncs with all my devices"&gt;Day One&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:dayoneshortcut"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:dayoneshortcut" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't want to make the Day One application open up every time that I finished something new so I looked at the &lt;a href="http://dayoneapp.com/tools/cli-man/" title="Day One command line interface"&gt;command line interface&lt;/a&gt; and came up with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mandaris/10543020504/" title="Screenshot of my keyboard maestro macro to log accomplishments quickly using the command line interface for Day One"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5487/10543020504_5edfa7b7ba.jpg" width="387" height="500" alt="Screenshot of my keyboard maestro macro to log accomplishments quickly using the command line interface for Day One"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, the only downside is that I have to go into Day One to make all the hashtags turn into tags and I have to do a search for that tag if I want to see all my accomplishments in a given time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think for the next iteration, I might set up &lt;a href="http://projects.tynsoe.org/en/geektool/" title="GeekTool: A tool to show information from files and commands on the desktop"&gt;GeekTool&lt;/a&gt; to show my latest accomplishment on my desktop, but I'm just happy that I finished this initial task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:unused"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought this &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Apple-Training-AppleScript-1-2-3-ebook/dp/B000SEI7EO/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1381753150&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=applescript+1-2-3"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; almost a year ago so that I could start teaching myself to do more automation on my computer. Turns out, I just needed to take the time and focus on something that I really wanted to create. It felt good and I think I'll actually get through it... when I get the time.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:unused" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:dayoneshortcut"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd already had a specific keyboard shortcut for opening up the menubar pop up for quick writing of thoughts and feelings, but I didn't want to add a &lt;a href="http://smilesoftware.com/TextExpander/index.html" title="Textexpander is a tool that I use when I'm writing things over and over again."&gt;textexpander&lt;/a&gt; snippet to add an accomplishment tag.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:dayoneshortcut" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="journal"></category><category term="accomplishments"></category><category term="keyboard maestro"></category></entry><entry><title>Messing around with Sublime Text</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2013/09/messing-around-with-sublime-text.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-16T10:56:13-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2013-09-16:2013/09/messing-around-with-sublime-text.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Honestly, a lot of people that I respect are talking about it. I think I'm going to have to step through the tutorial again. But honestly, I'd like to think about what I want to do with it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already have a couple text editors but I love messing around with the tools more than doing the job sometimes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only reason that I don't use sublime text is because of the price. The "free" demo allows you to use it as long as you want but you see a pop up reminding you that it hasn't been purchased yet. I'm not at a point where I can justify the price and being someone who works in the industry, I want to encourage people to pay for software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've talked to some other people and it seems like they are proud of the being able to mentally blockout the popup and dismiss it without missing a beat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, that just seems wrong on so many levels.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="software"></category><category term="sublime text"></category></entry><entry><title>QA Questions</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2013/09/qa-questions.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-12T22:09:38-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2013-09-12:2013/09/qa-questions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was recently asked to write a little something about my thoughts on doing QA and some questions about my experience. I was told to only write two sentences but I made three so that I could delete a paragraph later. I thought it would be ok to post them on my site. I hope that you get something out of reading it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a little bit of a perfectionist when it comes to my work. I find myself agonizing over details and often have multiple drafts and versions of emails, code examples and tutorials that I'm going to publish right after I change that one or two critical things that will make my point. This has been one of the reasons that I've been in Quality Assurance for as long as I have; I don't want people to run into problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started working, I was put in charge of creating and automating test suites for an application development tool. The mission was to simulate how a user would create a smaller application using the different components and options available. I quickly learned that automation is only good if you have a clear goal of what you want to accomplish. When the automation breaks, something should happen other than changing the automation. Since then, I've worked with a variety of systems that reported an issue when something goes wrong, either a problem in the build system or a change in functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of companies are attempting to be agile and it is important that a QA engineer keep up to date with where the company wants to go with the product and have an idea for how people are actually going to be using it. I've been in a couple of situations where companies have been so focused on the features of the product, that they loose track of how everything is supposed to come together for the user. There can be difficulty in communicating (development in remote parts of the world or just don't see it the same way), but I feel that I've learned a lot of different ways of getting my point across (detailed bug reports, screenshots and videos) and understanding where other people are coming from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In your current role, what is the end product? How do you test it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my current role, I test two products. One is a web portal that I test using selenium for regressions and manual testing following test plans that I've developed. The other is an IDE based off of eclipse which creates smaller applications that I do manual testing using test plans that I've created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Do you have experience with imbedded software? Please describe?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, the closest I've come to a truly imbedded system is when I was working at Intel and I had to run data through a simulation of the graphics chip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is your experience with programming? Languages? Years of experience? What have you programmed for?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've always been active in keeping my skills up. I've been doing java for about 8 years now and use it mainly for creating examples for customers and components within my test plans. I've used objective-c for 4 years and use it for my own personal applications. I've been getting more and more into python for the last 2 years as a way to automate my mac, generate test data and small web services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Have you been a member of a SCRUM team? Describe your sprints&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, most of them are related to creating and merging a major feature into the software. The team had to design and implement new features that could make the software unstable, I was in charge of merge conflicts and regression testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is your experience with defect tracking systems. Where did you do this and what was the project?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't imagine a world where there isn't some kind of defect tracking system! I've used RedMine, Jira, Salesforce and a couple built by the the company (Intel and Apple). At Unify, we used Salesforce to track customer issues and information. If there was a real bug or enhancement, we'd put it into Jira or a terminal based bug tracker and each person was told to make sure that all the information needed for a bug was completely documented and were to place test artifacts. At Intel and Apple, we used a custom built solution that required us to put the examples and test artifacts on a shared drive. At Intel, we also had to schedule time on simulator in order to reproduce and debug problems. At Starview, we use RedMine to document and prioritize issues as they come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Describe your experience with source control systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've used CVS, RCS, Subversion, git and mercurial. At intel, we used subversion to branch and merge bug features and bug fixes. It was my primary duty to handle these merges. The most difficult merge had to do with over 25 files and thousands of lines of code. At Starview, they use mercurial and I use the command line to interact with that. I use git to check out source control from Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Describe your experience with automated testing tools. What have you used? Where? For how long? In what context.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first tool that used was SilkTest as Unify, I used it for 2 years. At Intel, they had a system called Tambor that ran tests in an emulator (not to be confused with the simulator from earlier) part of the regression testing was running Tambor. Currently, I've been using Jenkins to start automated tasks when there is a change in source code. Jenkins kicks off tasks such as selenium to test how the application respond to user input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is your experience with integration test planning approaches and related experience with:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;regression testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, we add a test to the automated suite based off the the severity of the bug and all critical issues are added to the test plan for manual testing. Usually, this is broken down as use cases and there is a lot of over lap. For example, a new feature might be introduced (i.e when users click and hold a button a different event is triggered) and we have to make sure that the new functionality doesn't change how it used to work unexpectedly. I've had to write the plans that describe how it is supposed to be used and the code that would actually do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;acceptance testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At my current position, we noticed a problem where things started to feel slower when using the application. We didn't have any real data on how to see if there was a problem other than noticing that our automation suite was taking longer to run. I took it upon myself to learn and implement jmeter and look at serval plugins for jenkins so that we can look at the performance of different test from one build to the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;risk based testing?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually see this as part of regression testing because of time and resource limitations. If you are able to grow your suite of tests, you can focus on making sure that new features and bug fixes get higher priority for test creation. That being said, the new stuff is usually tested manually so that I can get a feel for what it is doing versus the documented requirements.
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="QA"></category><category term="employment"></category></entry><entry><title>N-Word</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2013/06/n-word.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-25T13:03:03-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2013-06-25:2013/06/n-word.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, it seems like even &lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/06/19/showbiz/paula-deen-racial-slur"&gt;Paula Deen&lt;/a&gt; has said it too. And it looks like a lot of people have a strong reaction to this. Her sponsor has dropped her and even the food network has severed her ties with her. "People" -I use the term loosely- are going back on forth on forums about how it's unfair to do this to her because some of the best selling rappers use the word like a particle of speech. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I think the outrage is too much. Doing this isn't helping race relations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;History?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to give you a history lesson on the N-word. Most people in America already know what it means. If you don't know what it means, take some time and watch &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0075572"&gt;Roots&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1853728"&gt;Django Unchained&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I can think about are my own experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My experiences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;People yelling it out of cars&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the times that I've heard the N-word shouted at me was when I had someone drive past me and yell the word from a moving vehicle. I've had people throw things at me as they were doing it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One instance was when our neighbor's boyfriend had yelled it at me after I had threatened to call the cops on him for yelling at his girlfriend. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of these people knew anything about me other than I was black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Children Yelling at Each Other&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when I take my kids to the park I hear some of the younger kids say it to each other. Sometime to intimidate and anger each other and other times as a general insult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sometimes see how some of the children will gang up on the other and use it in hopes that the one being teased (usually a smaller kid and never the largest) will fight back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if the kids are mimicking TV or just there life at home and feel sad for them that this is what they do when their parents are around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Entertainment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoy a lot of things, like music and movies. One of my favorite things to do is to watch a movie or listen to some stand up. In fact, some of my favorite comedians are Eddie Murphy, Chris Rock and Dave Chappelle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All three of them have had jokes that can be considered derogatory&lt;sup id="fnref:unfunny"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:unfunny" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to movies, a lot of the "black films" that I've seen in recent years have had the phrase "Nigga, please" or some kind of derivative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember a couple times, when I've had "discussions" with my parents about how I don't "talk black".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conference&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, the most memorable use of the N-word that I've heard happened when I was at a NSBE conference back in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speaker had painted an image of how a group of runaway slaves had been captured by some kind of bounty hunters and how some of them were going to be killed as an example. One of the runaways had just given birth and was pleading to be spared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slaver shot her dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then stomped the baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And said "Nigger".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As if it was less than trash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a powerful image, because it hit me that the N-word is the same word people would use to kill as to chide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That makes no sense to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Do other races see it that bad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know if other races, think about words used for them. And honestly, I've only know a couple. Most notably mexicans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What are we going to do?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we can all jump to arms and point fingers, but I doubt that is going to help anyone out in this situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Don't hide it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel we all need to be a little more open to the fact that people are going to say things that we don't like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And honestly, there are people out there that even the worst words are too good for them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is up to all of us to be a little understanding and let people express themselves&lt;sup id="fnref:DontBeStupid"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:DontBeStupid" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to a degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, how are they going to learn? And how are we going to know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a long way to go in race relations. I consider myself very lucky to be in America and even more lucky to be in California. I know we've made huge strides in equality and learning to live with other ethnic groups. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, there is more to this case than just the N-word. The lawsuit that brought this to light talks about other forms of harassment and I think that as human beings we should focus on that in regards to Paula Deen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:unfunny"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this might actually be why Eddie Murphy doesn't do stand up any more. I went back and listened to some of his earlier stuff and shook my head to hear how many "faggot" jokes he used to say.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:unfunny" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:DontBeStupid"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't be that guy who went to his child custody appearance dressed as &lt;a href="http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2013/06/hitler-dad-fights-for-custody-in-nazi-uniform.html"&gt;Hitler&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:DontBeStupid" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Bully, bully</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2013/03/bully-bully.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-17T22:42:31-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2013-03-17:2013/03/bully-bully.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tonight, my wife told me that our daughter has an exclusive girl club in her kindergarten class that she isn't allowed to be in. This club has one particular girl in it that is being mean to my daughter. She doesn't like being there &lt;sup id="fnref:aha"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:aha" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's something that no parent wants to hear, but should listen to now more than ever. &lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/2100-204_162-3239837.html" title="Girl's Suicide Rate Rise Dramatically"&gt;The suicide rate for girls has increased to an alarming level&lt;/a&gt; with articles and news clips talking about how girls are being ambushed and beaten by their peers. Then, to add more humiliation, someone records it and puts it on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some would say that it's just girls being mean, but I've been bullied and I know how these things can affect you. I only pray that I can help my daughter find the strength that she needs in order to get past this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:aha"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also makes since to why I see her playing by herself when I come into her class and why she's been acting up when she's at home.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:aha" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="bullying"></category></entry><entry><title>I almost bought BusyCal 2</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2013/03/i-almost-bought-busycal-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-13T00:07:33-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2013-03-07:2013/03/i-almost-bought-busycal-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been making little changes with my life in order to get more done instead of just talking about it. One of the changes that I've done is to become more committed to the things that I put into my calendar after hearing a couple great quotes from Merlin Mann's &lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/b2w" title="A great Podcast"&gt;Back to Work&lt;/a&gt; podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"A calendar is a map of your time." - Merlin Mann &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Don't let a calendar run your life, use a calendar to help &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; run your life." - Merlin Mann&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seemed like perfect timing that at the same time that I'm putting more effort into getting things together, one of flagship calendar applications - BusyCal - came out with a &lt;a href="https://support.busymac.com/tickets/15755" title="What's New in BusyCal 2.0"&gt;new version&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Organized&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the effort to become more organized, I decided that it would be easier on me to start off by placing recurring events and events that I know that I will certainly be attending. The only problem being that I need to review my calendar to make sure that it is up to date and that all the activities on my computer are reflected on the family calendar hanging on the wall of the kitchen. I'm slowly building up the habit of making sure that the two are in sync and in a way this works as a little review of what is going on in my life for the purpose of time management. Another benefit is that I don't commit to a lot of different things because of the hassle it would take to make sure that I'm available at a certain time&lt;sup id="fnref:punctual"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:punctual" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a way, this has improved how I function in my day to day life because I don't have as much stress about missing appointments. The stress I do have is generated because of my desire to do more things at once. The problem is that I'm getting a better idea of what I want/should be doing and it is kind of scary to see all the different things that are vying for my attention. I've been using &lt;a href="http://www.omnigroup.com/products/omnifocus" title="One of the most powerful/popular GTD applications in the world."&gt;OmniFocus&lt;/a&gt; to help me manage all the projects and I think I've moved a little bit past just pushing things around and doing busy work. I'm learning where things are getting lost and I think thats one of the key things you need to find if you really want to improve your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, this has really shown me that there isn't a silver bullet to being productive and getting things done. It's a bunch of little bullets being fired from the gun called willpower&lt;sup id="fnref:willpower"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:willpower" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. And I am starting to trust in myself to follow the plan that I have set out. I'm still working on making sure that I do some kind of as often as possible and get things out of my inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that leads us back to the main point of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why did/didn't buy BusyCal 2?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I'm on a budget. When you're constantly checking your balance to make sure that you have enough for food/rent/kids/spouse, it is hard to justify $30&lt;sup id="fnref:cash"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:cash" rel="footnote"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other reason is that I already have the first version of &lt;a href="http://www.busymac.com/busycal/index.html" title="BusyCal is an award winning calendar app that provides powerful time-saving productivity tools in a friendly, personalized, easy-to-use package."&gt;BusyCal&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://flexibits.com/fantastical" title="The Mac calendar you'll actually enjoy using"&gt;fantastical&lt;/a&gt;. Both of these products provide me with all the calendar information that I need at this point. For the current date and to add things, I use fantastical&lt;sup id="fnref:problem"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:problem" rel="footnote"&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. When it comes to a wider view, BusyCal does that way better that iCal in the sense that it isn't a nightmare to look at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had the money, I'd buy the new version as it looks really nice and company is focused on bringing a great mac experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:punctual"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while, I would stress out about meeting people up at a given time. I wanted my word to mean something when it came to not being late. If I said 8AM, I meant 8AM. In my mind, I would chant "Punctual is not being on time, it's being respectful of other peoples time". I still think that, but I don't stress about it.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:punctual" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:willpower"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That has to be one of the corniest things I've written in the last couple of weeks. &amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:willpower" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:cash"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's currently on sale until the end of the month. &amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:cash" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 3 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:problem"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although, I do have  a problem adding repeating events. I'm going to give the software the benefit of the doubt for not being able to read me  Maybe next release.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:problem" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 4 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="calendar"></category><category term="apps"></category></entry><entry><title>What do I want in an email client?</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2013/03/what-do-i-want-in-an-email-client.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-02T20:51:09-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2013-03-02:2013/03/what-do-i-want-in-an-email-client.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been thinking about email a lot more than I would like to during the last couple of days due to my latest attempt to have a GTD based workflow and eliminate some of the friction&lt;sup id="fnref:wonders"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:wonders" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in my life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know for a fact that email is not really the problem when it comes to managing my life and the thoughts about how to handle the incoming maybe just my minds way of just "moving the food around on my plate".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BUT&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been a problem for me every time that I get organized. I've been blessed to have two computers and it seems like a lot of trouble trying to get the two to have the same set up because I share one with the rest of the family and the other is my "work" computer that has all the latest do dads and what nots in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, I'm at a crossroads when it comes to my feelings about Mail.app and email/Gmail. I have multiple account (3 gmail accounts and 1 iCloud/me.com/MobileMe&lt;sup id="fnref:mobilemess"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:mobilemess" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). I feel that if I can't control this kind of input into my life than I'm not going to be able to trust any kind of system that I set up.  So made a little wish list of all the things that I need from an email client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard Shortcuts &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMAP/POP for when I "eventually" leave gmail&lt;sup id="fnref:free"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:free" rel="footnote"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scriptable/extendable - I want an easy way to send a link to a message to OmniFocus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stable - I want the app to do all of this without using plug-ins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where does this put me? Do I take the time to find that "Perfect" email client? Do I go back to Mail.app attempt to make it fit my imaginary workflow?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After writing all this, I think I'm just wasting my time with a first world problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:wonders"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More like distractions. I don't think I had a problem focusing on things until I had was able to get on the internet for longer than two hours in a row.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:wonders" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:mobilemess"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the longest time, it seemed like the service was constantly going down for hours or days at a time. I haven't heard of any problems in a while, but that could just mean that people don't care anymore.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:mobilemess" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:free"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to beat free. Although I'm paying for it by being a small aggregated blip on some data profile, I'm having trouble fighting "the good fight" and yes, I know that all the third party apps are using IMAP to connect to gmail.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:free" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 3 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="email"></category></entry><entry><title>Recollecting</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2013/02/recollecting.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-25T20:10:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2013-02-25:2013/02/recollecting.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I really like doing a brain dump/collection in the GTD sense. It gives me a feeling that I can actually control it all. That I'm going to rediscover every last commitment that I've got to make and then be able to make my world just a little bit better. I think that I've finally reached the point when I'm no longer running from all my insecurities.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="collection"></category></entry><entry><title>Served</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2013/02/served.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-22T23:21:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2013-02-22:2013/02/served.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well after having nightmares about it for the last couple of nights, I can now rest easy now that the pancake breakfast is over. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what a breakfast it was, at first things were moving really slowly as the people trickled two and three at a time and I was actually afraid that we wouldn't be able to make enough money to break even with the costs of all the supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then the boom dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found myself constantly mixing batter to keep up with a constant stream of hungry customers. In fact, I heard that there was a story of people who went through the line 3 times.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Night wrap up</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2013/02/night-wrap-up.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-21T23:10:06-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2013-02-21:2013/02/night-wrap-up.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, Im going to be leading the parents of my daughters kindergarten class in our first and only fundraiser. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The (in)famous pancake breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was an activity that they told us about at the very beginning of the school year (6 months ago) and Ive honestly have been kind of dreading that this day would come. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its not so much volunteering to do it as it is getting the parents to help out. Although our school has a policy where every parent is required to volunteer 40 hours over the entire school year or donate 20 bucks per hour, I feel that not everyone is able to jump on board and help support us with this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im not angry and I understand that not everyone can help this week, but since Im the one who is responsible for this if it fails...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im just happy that the class that my daughter is in has a lot of top notch parents who really want this to succeed and understand that even the little bit of help can go a long way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially if you tell me about it so I dont go crazy thinking about what could go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing of personal note is that all the stress of the pancake breakfast has gotten me back in front of the computer to write again.  There have been a number of moments that Ive been wishing for my journal and tonight is one of them.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Short Complaint</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2013/02/short-complaint.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-02T07:02:19-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2013-02-02:2013/02/short-complaint.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I do not like the new open dialog for Mac OSX. I think that it is one of the most annoying changes to the UX in a very long time. Every time I want to just create a simple note, it slows me down with the question about where the heck I want to save the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I just dont care and want to write something down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SHIT.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="observation"></category></entry><entry><title>Passion for the wife</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/11/passion-for-the-wife.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-13T23:24:34-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-11-13:2012/11/passion-for-the-wife.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I dont think society OKs me saying this but I love making passionate love to my wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shes good at it and I love doing it with her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When its great.:
Which is actually turning into a question because weve been having a couple of issues in the bedroom. Sometime it great and sometime both of us are left laying there unsatisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know Im not the only one this has happened to. A multimillion dollar industry is aimed at couples, women and men trying to improve what they have in the bed room or at the very least make &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weve done a couple things like read books, play games and even watch a movie or two, but Im coming to the conclusion that we are missing that little spark that used to set us off. Sure, we have are little sessions here and there but I feel that weve drifted apart in some ways and it doesnt feel like we are making love to each other but only attempting to satisfy our desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how do we do that? How do I take the woman who nurtures my kids and kisses there owies and do all the little things I wanted to do when we were dating?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it me? Am I the one who is having trouble identifying that woman I married as the same woman who I couldnt get the clothes off fast enough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of it is that I cant get my mind on all the thoughts about being in adequate and into the moment where it is just two people trying to connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the kids wake up.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="marriage"></category></entry><entry><title>What am I going to do in this moment?</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/11/what-am-i-going-to-do-in-this-moment.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-12T21:35:32-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-11-12:2012/11/what-am-i-going-to-do-in-this-moment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ive thought about it. The desires of my life. About what I would I would do if I could do it in an instant. What would I do if I were to snap my fingers and the thing that I wanted were to magically happen; whether it was instantly get into shape or finish that book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is in these moments of clarity that I come closer to the reality that if I want to realize these hopes and dreams that I must first start towards them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A journey of a thousand miles began with a single step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, Im not going to beat myself up about the steps I havent taken. There isnt any point in doing that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im not going to freak out about what tools to use or what direction to go in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im going to sit here, not afraid of what obstacles and hurdles I may run into or worry that Im going the wrong way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im going to take this moment and be thankful for the opportunities that I have in front of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im alive and in good health. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a family downstairs reading to each other and living in the moment created by the universe just for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finish this little piece of writing, Im going down to be with them knowing that although I have millions and millions of possibilities for things to do, I only have so many moments to be with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is a kind of peace of mind that money or dreams cant buy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="observation"></category></entry><entry><title>Just when it gets good</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/08/just-when-it-gets-good.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-08-28T22:34:22-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-08-28:2012/08/just-when-it-gets-good.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It seems like everything things get good between my wife and I things seem to fall apart. I don't know what it is but it feels like the problem I'm having with my mom. I.E. things go well and then &lt;strong&gt;GRRRRRR&lt;/strong&gt; we're silently fighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm afraid that I married my mom in that regard. I've married someone who's default behavior is something akin to a wild animal. Even when you think she's pretty tamed, she'll rear back and swipe at you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that isn't even the worst part about it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst part is that there are very rarely moments where I feel that she even notices it herself or feels that she maybe in the wrong. When we talk about it. I usually hear "you do it too" as if makes it right and a brush off that the argument is over. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel blooded and scared over it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been thinking about the story of the scorpion and the frog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A scorpion and a frog meet on the bank of a stream and the 
scorpion asks the frog to carry him across on its back. The 
frog asks, "How do I know you won't sting me?" The scorpion 
says, "Because if I do, I will die too."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frog is satisfied, and they set out, but in midstream,
the scorpion stings the frog. The frog feels the onset of 
paralysis and starts to sink, knowing they both will drown,
but has just enough time to gasp "Why?" &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replies the scorpion: "Its my nature..."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it is our nature, maybe it is something being blown out of proportion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you felt your relationship was sinking, what would you do?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="relationships"></category><category term="marriage"></category></entry><entry><title>Bed time patience</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/08/bed-time-patience.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-03-06T12:07:07-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-08-20:2012/08/bed-time-patience.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today has been a pretty good day. I got up and was able to get a breakfast for my kids and get them to school on time followed by some quality time with my youngest&lt;sup id="fnref:youngest"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:youngest" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things were going pretty good even though there were a number of bumps along the way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then its time for bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like this is the most difficult time for my family&lt;sup id="fnref:routine"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:routine" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and it is the one that really tries my patience because it is the end of the day and is the last that stands between me and any activities that I want or need to do for that day. I feel that it is because the lack of a consistent schedule is a major reason my wife and I have issues with communication and... um... other stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:youngest"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The youngest asked me to pack up a lunch for her and put it in her backpack. I packed the same lunch as I did for my oldest as she requested and then when we got to class she wanted to touch all the toys and wanted to stay after the bell was rung. I had to bribe her with playing my little pony when we got home AND a piggy back ride.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:youngest" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:routine"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is the fault of me and my wife as we do not instill a stable routine with the girls. Too often, we get derailed with activities or some other nonsense like not using the right toothpaste, etc.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:routine" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="routine"></category></entry><entry><title>I like to read</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/08/i-like-to-read.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-08-17T01:30:37-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-08-17:2012/08/i-like-to-read.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like the idea of being a writer. i also like the idea of being a programmer. I spend a lot of time reading about what this and that person did an invariably putthem on a little bit of a pedistal. After that I stand back and say "that person is cool. I wonder if I could do something cool like that. I know, I'll takesome notes and then when I get a chance I'll make something must as cool."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing comes from just wanting and -at this point- my dreams are only hurting me because I see these people and only see what i lack versus what i can bring to the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like im hurting and i dont know if I'll ever  heal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell myself it ok. That I can get up and do something more with my life but it feels like all my breaks are simply to break even. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need some kind of guidence.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="writing"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Loosing touch</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/07/loosing-touch.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-23T23:48:32-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-07-23:2012/07/loosing-touch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, I really feel like I'm loosing touch with my daughters. Part of me thinks that I maybe overthinking the fact that I've been a little sick and out of it the last couple of days, but another part is worried about the health of the communication between me and my 4 year old daughter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as I wrote that I thought to myself, 'How can any one unstand the mind of a 4 year old?'. Well, there are books on it so maybe something is there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Using your big girl words&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, it feels that our daughters are both not communicating in the best possible way. Both of them seem to yell and whine more than they used to and I find myself thinking that this might be my fault since they are home more. The last couple of weeks have seen the family move into a pattern where things aren't really moving as in a healthy way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it's the lack of sleep or the fact that mommy and daddy have had more and more conflict where we aren't talking to each other in a respectful way and the children sometimes hear us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it's the fact that our dog died and this is part of the grieving process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever it is, we have to figure it out and find a way for us as a family to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The alternative diffinitely won't make anyone happy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="children"></category></entry><entry><title>Our first painting project</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/07/our-first-painting-project.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-22T21:00:55-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-07-22:2012/07/our-first-painting-project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, the wife and I finished up a two day painting project involving some furniture that my mom had found at a yard sale. At first I had my own reservations about taking the furniture in because of all the invisible strings attached to something like that&lt;sup id="fnref:mama_drama"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:mama_drama" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was told that it was going to be a simple set of headboards, drawers and a desk with a little book shelf on top. In truth, the furniture was a lot different then what we were expecting as far as shape, size and quality. It's the older kind of furniture, the kind that can last and be moved from one home to another without falling apart along the way. It looked like it could take a beating and from some of the scratches and scraps it looked like it already had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the wife decided that we should paint it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this turned into a weekend long project where we spent most of our time outside in the sun putting multiple coats of white and pink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And just when we finish up and show our children. How do they react?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They hate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:mama_drama"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't like taking things from people because they sometimes expect you to reciprocate in a way that I don't feel warrants a particular action. I'm grateful for everything, but it feels like sometimes there is an unspoken contract and a payment that is beyond what I'm willing to do. Sorry for being vague and extra appologizies if this sounds like I'm talking about you. I'm not it's someone completely different.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:mama_drama" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="home"></category></entry><entry><title>All morning long</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/07/all-morning-long.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-17T11:53:54-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-07-17:2012/07/all-morning-long.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last night the wife and I were up late last night.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Ticking Clock</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/07/ticking-clock.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-17T11:36:14-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-07-17:2012/07/ticking-clock.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Currently, I'm sitting in an office waiting for my friend to get finished talking to his doctor. I've been doing this for the last couple of weeks, and it is has been nice to see my friend a little bit more. I feel that we've both have been walking our own paths and neither one of us is happy about it. When we see each other, we get a chance to talk about our own grievances and help cheer each other on as we make our way towards are respective goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, I've been playing with the idea of doing affirmations and spending time everyday writing out 5 things that I'm excited/happy about as well as grateful for&lt;sup id="fnref:grateful"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:grateful" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for my friend, I don't know all the things that he is doing to relieve stress and just move forward with his life. I kind of just want to give him a big hug and tell him that it's going to be alright, but I know that isn't going to be enough. It isn't enough for me either and when it comes to stuff like this, you have make your own choices on how you are going to make yourself a better person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:grateful"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as I typed it, I realized that Day One would be perfect for something like that because it would allow me to keep track of those without having all the roadblocks that I would put in front of a normal writing routine.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:grateful" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="time"></category><category term="friends"></category></entry><entry><title>Working out is hard to do</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/07/working-out-is-hard-to-do.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-16T21:09:19-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-07-16:2012/07/working-out-is-hard-to-do.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, the whole family went running. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="exercise"></category></entry><entry><title>The day after have a big argument with my wife sucks.</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/07/the-day-after-have-a-big-argument-with-my-wife-sucks.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-13T21:11:32-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-07-13:2012/07/the-day-after-have-a-big-argument-with-my-wife-sucks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It sucks soooo bad that I sometimes wonder why I even bother in the first place. Was the subject of what we were fighting over so big that we have to go through this? Do the highs of our relationship really outweigh the lows?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of me tells me to just relax  because this is part of what relationships are about. Highs and lows. We've been having some rough spots because I've lost my job and the money has gotten a lot tighter&lt;sup id="fnref:tighter"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:tighter" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. We both have our expectations of what should and shouldn't be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another part of me is angry at the world. Angry at where I am. Angry at myself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was having a fairly good day and I didn't want to walk into that familiar routine of being &lt;em&gt;her&lt;/em&gt; punching bag. I'm tired of taking other people's &lt;code&gt;redacted&lt;/code&gt; and I dumped it back on her with other stuff as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then she just laughed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's where I went wrong. I got angry. I got very angry and said that I sometimes don't like coming home to her because of her attitude. I might have said some other stuff too. I don't remember all of it, but I'm sure she'll remind&lt;sup id="fnref:remember"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:remember" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went for a walk before it got bigger. I came home. We didn't look at each other. She took the girls. We slept in separate rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I'm sitting at a coffee shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might as well be sitting in the middle of Antarctica for all the distance and coldness between us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:tighter"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real rub about this is that even though I'm unemployed, I still make more than her via unemployment insurance. This has allowed us to appear that we are doing alright, but I feel the strain of it. We're living &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/9iCd6UHR-3I" title="Still Fly"&gt;hood rich&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:tighter" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:remember"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to paraphrase, "There are three sides to every story: The way he remembers it, the way she remembers it, what really happened."&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:remember" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="relationships"></category></entry><entry><title>Speaking of making myself a priority</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/07/speaking-of-making-myself-a-priority.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-11T23:45:57-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-07-11:2012/07/speaking-of-making-myself-a-priority.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I went for a run today by myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't had any exercise in a while and it was great to get out of my head and hit the dusty trail... which actually isn't dusty because it's paved. Although I do enjoy the benefits of running, I don't really enjoy it. I don't get a thrill of having the wind in my hair or seeing the scenery change as I speed along the paths and trails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I'm not going that fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, I plan on going to my first yoga class at a local studio and I'm pretty excited about it. It's a new way of caring for myself and I have to make that a priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Speaking of making myself a priority&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've typed up a new list of affirmations for myself, but I'm honestly afraid to put them in a place that I can see them every day. I've played with the idea of making a script to pop them up when I first log into my computer in the morning, but that time usually changes depending on what I'm doing that day. I've also thought about putting them up in the bathroom, but I'm embarrassed about how I would explain that to my children and afraid that my wife might say something about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at that last sentence and thought, 'Hey, I can't live that way. If I'm going to make myself a better person, I need to do this for me.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I guess I'll be printing them up now.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="exercise"></category></entry><entry><title>Dark Dream</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/07/dark-dream.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-10T14:00:16-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-07-10:2012/07/dark-dream.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was in a dark place. It was a cage with other people and a couple lights above us. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could hear people walking across and i knew who they were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were being judged and they were going to heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and then a man came down dressed in black and drinking a cup of coffee. he asked "why should you live?" as he sipped his drink and sat down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"how can i find my pashion," i yelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;he almost spat out his coffee... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;he readjusted himself in the chair and repeated the question as if i hadnt said anyhting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i felt like i was doomed and helpless. that nothing i said or did would change anything...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i feeling that im too familiar with...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and then the alarm went off.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dream"></category></entry><entry><title>Considering my task managment</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/07/considering-my-task-managment.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-02T20:12:03-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-07-02:2012/07/considering-my-task-managment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A while ago I came across some questions to consider everytime that I do a review of my tasks. The problem is that I've attached the questions to a task in OmniFocus and -honestly- I don't think it's helpful to do something like that unless I think and write about it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this system trustworthy? If not, why not? Do I need to make better backups?&lt;br /&gt;
No, there are two major problems with the personal productivity. The first is that I don't schedule enough time for something. How can I finish a task when I don't make any time for it. Secondly, I don't do enough positive reviews. I need to do a review every day to make sure that tasks don't fall through the cracks and I don't overwhelm myself. I find most of my reviews are when I'm under the gun. Not a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there a next actionable task? Can it actually be readily done?&lt;br /&gt;
Yes... for the most part. I have a couple projects that have items like "Brainstorm next action".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When do I anticipate looking at this next actions context?&lt;br /&gt;
This goes back to the first question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will this project look like when it is done?
Depends on the project, baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When do I think Ill need to see this project again?&lt;br /&gt;
That also depends on the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="goals"></category><category term="productivity"></category></entry><entry><title>Get your own!</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/06/get-your-own.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-06-07:2012/06/get-your-own.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So for the last couple of months I've been carrying a large spiral notebook that I got from staples. I had planned on using it to capture ideas and as The One Tool&lt;sup id="fnref:tool"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:tool" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that would change all of my disorganization into a simple constantly productive life. As will all my new tools it was great for getting thoughts down and being able to read them over. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only major problem I had was that I could put it in my pocket and just leave right away, I had to have some kind of bag or give up a free hand in order to carry it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing is that my daughters see it and think "Hey, it drawing time" and now it's halfway filled with their little snippets of stories and artwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, it's made it even easier to keep around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:tool"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a recovering productivity porn junky. I think a log of perfectionist/procrastinators are always looking for that one thing that will wip away all her or his problems away. The should all look into .&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:tool" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="parenting"></category><category term="productivity"></category></entry><entry><title>Blogging workshop</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/05/blogging-workshop.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-03-06T12:30:51-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-05-16:2012/05/blogging-workshop.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I went to a blogging workshop and I found it really interesting. At first, I was worried that it would filled with the standard novice information like how to get on the internet being taught by someone took 15 minutes to get some information off the internet and put it into a powerpoint presentation to read to use.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="blog"></category><category term="writing"></category></entry><entry><title>Addiction to the iPad</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/05/addiction-to-the-ipad.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-04T21:52:17-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-05-04:2012/05/addiction-to-the-ipad.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My oldest daughter has fallen in love with our iPad. She has gone from being an avid reader to coming home and asking for it as soon as she steps through the door. Sometimes she even asks for it as we drive up to our home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of me is proud about how she has mastered moving around on the device. I've sometimes seen her start a movie in Netflix or watching things on YouTube. My wife loves telling her co-workers how our daughters can do things that some adults have difficulty doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that is part of the problem. My daughter &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do things other adult have trouble doing. Things like place an item into an Amazon shopping cart and proceed to the check out, find "special" offers on Disney  merchandise and then place her personal information in one of the forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I've been lucky that she hasn't ordered hunders of books and horse toys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of this problem is that she's grown rather fond of a series of fan fiction trailers about the Lion King. Although at first glance there isn't anything wrong with seeing how people can take something and make it so much more. When she run over to me and says that certain characters share a different relationship and lineage that I feel is &lt;em&gt;kosher&lt;/em&gt; that's when I got to step on the breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe, part of this is my fault for pushing technology and all it's wonderful whizz bangs without giver her some kind of limitations. But the geek in my wanted to see what she could do if she were to explore on her own. The part of me that says "you must always be a vigilant parent" lost to the part of that wants to let her be free and a kid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is what makes this part bitter sweet. I know the world isn't filled with magical talking animals. My daughter knows this too. But there is no need to disillusion her to the good in people and the good of moral character. She doesn't need to worry about wether Simba and Nala are really first cousins. She doesn't need to worry about a whole bunch of books showing up that she needs to pay for. She shouldn't worry about meeting some stranger on the internet. She needs to just have fun and be a kid.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="tech"></category><category term="parenting"></category></entry><entry><title>A life filled with life</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/05/a-life-filled-with-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-01T22:50:48-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-05-01:2012/05/a-life-filled-with-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I feel that one of my greatest weaknesses is that I underestimate myself and my abilities. For a large part of my life, I've had a voice in my head that told me that I'm not good enough. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not good enough to be a writer, so I never took the time to write.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not good enough to be a dancer, so I never pursued competition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not good enough to make it as a programmer, so I never submitted an application to anyone other than teachers and close friends and afterward I never bothered to save my own code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not pretty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is only when I stop myself and look at all the little things that I do and make a daily list of accomplishments that I find the strength say, "Yes, I can and did."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They say life is made up of little things, and it is up to all of us to find the little things in life that will move us forward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One time, I said that I'd rather live a life where I regretted some of the outcomes of things that I'd done rather than living with the regret that I didn't do anything. Turns out that I was living a life filled with simple regret instead of going out there and just living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to get on the horn and start outlining all the things that I plan on doing because I know how plans can change. All I can do is be true to myself and look at how I can change my course to live my dreams...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Late night write</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/04/late-night-write.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-19T22:52:48-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-04-19:2012/04/late-night-write.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, here I am lying in bed with my iPad typing away in Byword. I feel that today was a great day I got a lot of things done early and although I didn't finish everything that I wanted, I feel that the sense of accomplishment is well deserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, I've got a couple obligations to handle and I'm planning that it shouldn't be an obstacle if I start the day the as today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Washing Sierra's car&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm actually a little worried about this task tomorrow, because it's a very large van and I don't think that Sierra has everything he needs to get the job done or twill e en be up in time to start working on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I think it will be good to see him and work on something together. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Planning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel the best thing that's happened is a change of perspective about my life and... Well... Not feeling sorry for myself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized that I could wallow in dispare or I could take that time and energy to feel good about myself and make things better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is what you make it whether you actively make the choice or let it take you some place.... And from what I've seen and experienced it rarely takes you to good places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Morning review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think ive talked about this before and I think it is even more important when you are unemployed. if you don't review the days shrink into hours and the hours into meer minutes and the pressure and depression pound on more as you wonder what is the point of sitting in front of a monitor searching for rejection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you review, not just your tasks at hand but why you are actually doing it. if you think about how your actions are supposed to move along some kind of plan -even if it's not fully realized- they become easier, almost effortless.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Declaratives for the day</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/04/declaratives-for-the-day.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-18T07:14:33-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-04-18:2012/04/declaratives-for-the-day.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, I'm going to nock some things off of my project list for a while now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that I'm going to do after dropping off the kids is redo my website. I've put up a place holder for now, but I'm sick of not having a place on the internet that isn't really mine. I'm going to have a really basic design and then just take it from there. I think I might even place it back onto NearlyFreeSpeech.net again because they had one of the easier ways of hosting and I didn't have to worry about forwarding the www.quotidianquest.com&lt;sup id="fnref:www"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:www" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I think one other thing about this project is to finish my version of my formatting markdown script. I've been pushing it back for quite a while and I can't get it off of my mind. I'd really like to have something to show the world and just be able to move on with something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for my other project that I'm going to be moving on to. I'm going to work on my trust issues with my project tracking system. I don't review it often enough to trust it and I find myself letting things fall by the way side. I think I'm going to focus on getting things out of my mind and dedicating time on my calendar to review things at the beginning and end of the day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:www"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know if that's really an issue any more, but it really bugs me that that isn't working when I'm hosting on github. But hosting on github is free and free is really hard to beat. &amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:www" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>I've decided</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/04/ive-decided.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-09T07:45:37-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-04-09:2012/04/ive-decided.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've decided to start the day off swinging. It certainly helps to already have some kind of plan for the day and I want to take advantage of this great energy that I've got and really finish something. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="starting over"></category></entry><entry><title>Giving Byword another chance</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/04/giving-byword-another-chance.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-08T11:13:36-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-04-08:2012/04/giving-byword-another-chance.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've decided to give Byword on iOS a norther chance. The first time I tried it I found it to be a little too unstable and (more a personal matter) too different than the other ways of writing that im used to&lt;sup id="fnref:keyboard"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:keyboard" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Byword is actually the first text editor that I bought. I've attempted to use simple note as well as the notes application that came with all iOS devices. I stopped using simple note because of a little syncing issue between it, nvalt and Dropbox. I might give it another chance because I've simplified my writing and reduced some of the complexity of my thoughts but we will see how all of this turns out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess that is really the heart of my problem with Byword on iOS, I couldn't really see how it would perform in my "workflow". If I used iCloud sync, it seemed that I wouldn't be able to achieve the files with the rest of my snippets and push them to my blog as I would like to. the dropbox support was kind of weird as I saw multiple copies sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why am I using it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, after losing my job, I fell off of my writing wagon and I found myself just wandering between submitting job applications. I got lost in the tools and focusing on my lack of writing instead of making it happen for me. I figured that if it's alright to get back on the writing horse, then it should be alright to give this tool another chance to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, it just text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:keyboard"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I've had a iPad for more than a year, I find typing on the screen a little weird.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:keyboard" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="writing"></category></entry><entry><title>I met Ted Landau</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/03/i-met-ted-landau.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-20T20:43:23-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-03-20:2012/03/i-met-ted-landau.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At today's &lt;a href="http://www.macnexus.org/"&gt;macnexus&lt;/a&gt; meeting we had &lt;a href="http://tedlandau.com/"&gt;Ted Landau&lt;/a&gt; come speak about the IOS-ification of Mac OS X and I found it to be rather enjoyable. I agreed with a lot of his points about how certain changes to the OS could be a good thing that it would help all the new recruits&lt;sup id="fnref:recruits"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:recruits" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; get used to the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem for me is that it hasn't been easy for me. Some of the things that I've grown accustomed to were changed in Lion and it took a while to get used&lt;sup id="fnref:annoy"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:annoy" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to them or find the best way to work around them. I've since grown used to the dip in performance as certain animations have played out and I even enjoy the way some Mail.app works (to a degree).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My problem is that I still feel that certain things aren't being taken care of properly. I've created a little list of some of my continuing gripes with Lion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/whats-new/mission-control.html"&gt;Mission Control&lt;/a&gt; doesn't fully replace Spaces&lt;br /&gt;
I understand that Mission Control is supposed to be more accessible for users and -honestly- I turned Spaces on and off sometimes when I was attempting different workflows, but it seems that takes more work in order to use it. With Spaces, you could assign different application to different desktops, but if you want that in Lion, you have to put the applications into the different spaces by yourself and hopefully you don't need to restart or anything. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's the deal with FrontRow?&lt;br /&gt;
If I had a dollar for every time that someone told me to use &lt;a href="http://www.plexapp.com/"&gt;Plex&lt;/a&gt; instead, I'd have at least enough money to get a value meal. If I had a dollar for every person who used the feature minus the guy who tells me to use Plex, at best I'd break even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Address book&lt;br /&gt;
I doubt who ever OK'd didn't already have all or most of his contacts already sorted. Navigating between different groups and then putting people into the right place is painful and the interface is ugly. Yes, I've looked at &lt;a href="http://www.cobookapp.com/"&gt;cobooks.app&lt;/a&gt; and I think it's trying too hard to look nice for something I plan on just updating and closing 95% of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting to the point&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so after going over some of the same problems that I was having with Lion. We had a Q&amp;amp;A session where he said that despite all of these issues he's looking forward to &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/mountain-lion/"&gt;Mountain Lion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was actually a little suprised by this, but he said it with such sincerity that it actually hit me like a mini &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reality_distortion_field"&gt;reality distortion field&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was at peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things are going to get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then the wave was over and I felt like a storm trooper that just let an old man and a kid scoot on by with the droids that I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:recruits"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaning all the users of iPad and iPhones who buy a Mac after seeing how easy the software can be used.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:recruits" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:annoy"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I actually had a need for contacts, I'd be sooo pissed right now. Everytime I use it, I want to delete it and I haven't found a suitable replacement that isn't a bunch of fluff trying to get you to connect to facebook or something like that. &amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:annoy" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="OSX"></category></entry><entry><title>The fog of war</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/03/the-fog-of-war.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-18T23:28:52-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-03-18:2012/03/the-fog-of-war.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don't know where I'm going to be next week at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are the first words that I can think of as I stare at the computer trying to come up with something write about for today. It's not that I don't know what I'll be doing&lt;sup id="fnref:doing"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:doing" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but what am I going to be thinking about when I do it. Will I be worried about when my next paycheck is going to come in or am I going to happy that we just finished another birthday party for the kids. Will I have to worry about whether or not I have to put the dog down because he's been having some digestive problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been looking for ways to not get into a rut since loosing my job almost a month ago. All I can think of is the worry about what my next step is going to be and how horrible it will be if such and such doesn't happen for me. Almost none of my energy has gone into making things happen for me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It almost feels like I'm catatonic, or a ghost standing over my own body and watching as time and life just slip by me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only good news is that I feel that I'm finally slipping through some of the fog and actually moving forward with some things again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like with a lot of things in life, the first step is the hardest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:doing"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most probably looking for a job or something like that.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:doing" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>swelling</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/03/swelling.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-12T22:19:21-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-03-12:2012/03/swelling.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My wife had her wisdom teeth removed last Friday and she's still in pain. They say that if momma ain't happy then no one is&lt;sup id="fnref:momma"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:momma" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but -other than the occasional rough spot brought by the fact that she's in pain and can't eat- it's pretty smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, it's given me more opportunities to interact with the girls and show them that I can be just as fun as mommy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, my youngest usually screams like a banshee when we clean her hair, but we turned it into a fun game where she got to play with the shower head and squirt around the bath tub. Both of them liked it and we didn't have to clean up buckets of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Working Out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had my second workout at innovative fitness but I think that it could have been better. Most of the exercises are new to me and I'm spending more of my time focusing on the technique versus pushing myself a little bit harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My knees have been hurting me when I do lunges and the exercises that the couch has been throwing at us has some kind of lunge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that it might be what's holding me back. I'm scared of pain. I don't want to hurt myself, but it made me think about all the times that I didn't push myself because it hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:momma"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also say what's good for goose is good for gander. I used to think that was talking about feeding birds... Oh, to be young and naive.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:momma" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="relationship"></category></entry><entry><title>Who is the father?</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/03/who-is-the-father.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-11T23:19:51-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-03-11:2012/03/who-is-the-father.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was driving over to the post office to drop off my unemployment papers and I was thinking about my father. I do respect and love my father, but sometimes I see the scars that life has given him. There are moments where I see the bitterness seeping out of him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I lived in his house for more than half of my life, there are many things I don't know about him. I don't know all the troubles he lived through and there have been times when I've wondered why does he feel a certain way about different things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been many times that he's ranted about something and I've thought he was crazy. The thing is that's I feel that he's right to a degree, but the way he talks about it doesn't help his argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, I don't know much about my father outside of being &lt;em&gt;my father&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is important?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it important that I know everything about my dad before he became my dad? No. The important thing is that he loves me and that I can trust him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons I think about this is that I wonder if he is happy. Is he proud of the majority of his choices in life and whether he's accomplished all of the goals that were truly important to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Are we going anywhere with this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many times in my life where I've forgotten that how many sibilings that my parent have and what's their names are. I do know that my father has a brother... His name in John. I don't know if it's Jon, Jonathan or John... For a couple of years I thought it was Robert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I was driving in the car with my family and I mentioned my brother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My oldest daughter asked, "You got a brother?"&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="family"></category></entry><entry><title>Naruto 577 review</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/03/naruto-577-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-10T23:17:42-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-03-10:2012/03/naruto-577-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend an I usually talk about manga every week via chat or email, mostly about &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Naruto"&gt;Naruto&lt;/a&gt; which we've been reading and watching for almost a decade. Recently, it seems like the series is coming to an end as the author has really cranked up the stakes, action and WTF factors in the story. At this point, I'm reading because I care about the characters and I really want to find some closure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if the story goes a little crazy sometimes, it's still a lot better than &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bleach_(manga)"&gt;bleach&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I had almost forgotten that I had read this week's issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sasuke, Sasuke, Sasuke. I haven't read a good story line with that guy in it since he fought Gaara. Him and his brother are like poo and every time they touch the plot....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the 5 &lt;a href="http://naruto.wikia.com/wiki/Kage"&gt;Kages&lt;/a&gt;, although they are supposed to be the embodiment of their respective villages will and stuff they all have some kind of weird weekness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hokage (Tsunade): Medical ninja with a gambling and drinking problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kazekage (Gaara): Recently resolved daddy issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mizukage (Mei Terumi): A woman&lt;sup id="fnref:woman"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:woman" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; ;P... but seriously, single note character&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raikage (A... stupid name for killer bee's brother): One arm...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tsuchigake (Onoki): Old&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus they've been fighting all day and this is an undead opponent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry about the long email. Just had a roll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:woman"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The manga, although it has some positive women, it's rare to find ones that are have any real depth of character.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:woman" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="manga"></category><category term="review"></category></entry><entry><title>Teeth and projects</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/03/teeth-and-projects.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-09T21:55:59-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-03-09:2012/03/teeth-and-projects.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My wife had her wisdom teeth pulled today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All four of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, things are going to be cheery around here. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent most of the day just caring for her or watching her sleep. It was kind of nice because it took me back to the early days of our relationship when I would just sit and stare as she slept. Natasha thought it was kind of creepy, but for me it was a rare moment of seeing her at peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've prioritized my tech projects to two major things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The website&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've taken my website down because I didn't like the direction (or lack thereof) it was taking. I originally had a lot of different ideas that I wanted to do, but got stuck with the tools on making it versus making the content the king. I've placed a holding page up for now while I come up with what the next step is going to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't decided on whether I should move to a service lie calipin or just throw everything out and start completely from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Re-starting my career&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not happy with where I am and have decided that I need to start over from the very begining as far as my career is concerned. I'd like to take what I know about computer science and just go over all the little things that made me take the subject from the beginning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On how to do this, I've been putting a plan together that focuses more on the how of computer science and "going deep" versus the why.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="wife"></category><category term="programming"></category></entry><entry><title>Books and Job Hunting</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/03/books-and-job-hunting.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-08T15:40:03-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-03-08:2012/03/books-and-job-hunting.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, today I was thinking about all the things I would like to do. Sometimes it feels like I have the entire world on my shoulders and I fight the urge to attempt to do everything at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to take a second to think about what the most important thing is at this moment and do it to the best of my ability. It times like this, I go back to OmniFocus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I attempted to ship a book[^book] that I had placed on Amazon. Amazon was going to give me 3 bucks to ship it and all the shipping options that USPS offered were 4 dollars or more. I like the idea of sharing knowledge but I seriously don't want to donate my money and time in this fashion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Job Hunting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been looking for a job on dice.com and it strikes me as interesting on how different job postings can be. Some of them are very simple and might as well be the equivelent of a "Help Wanted" sign while others might have 30 or more requirements in order to apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my last interview, the person I spoke with was actually surprised that I read the psoting and job description. Which got me thinking about the hotgun versus snipper rifle approach to job hunting. Do you focus on getting as many rsum out there or do you make a custom one for every kind of position and a different covers letters for every position?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="jobs"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>App Store Reviews and Sweat</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/03/app-store-reviews-and-sweat.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-07T22:45:15-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-03-07:2012/03/app-store-reviews-and-sweat.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tonight, I wrote a review for &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/monopoly-hotels/id479412611?mt=8"&gt;MONOPOLY Hotels&lt;/a&gt;, because I was wanted to rant against what I see as a societal evil. Here it is below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's hard for me to understand why some many other people like this game so much. Haven't we all learned the lessons of freemium? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game starts off free, but in the end it become a very long grind where the only way to make some kind of progress is to pay money for "gold". There is no way that you hard work can balance against that kind of thing and if you spent that much time doing it, just think about what you could have been doing with that time and energy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a hint: Maybe make your own&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oooo! Harsh, I know. You can actually see society changing as you read every character, but I think the ending is the most important. I would like to see a game that was fun and rewarded players for the hard work that they do but still let those who want to "win" do so. I think I'll spend the next couple of days working on some prototypes to see how much work it would take to make something like this come to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fitness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was my first time in the gym all year... and maybe all of last year too and I have to say that it was great. I went to innovative fitness and conditioning and it almost seemed like I was having my own personal trainer... that I shared... with 6 people. &lt;em&gt;BUT&lt;/em&gt; I don't think I could have done all the exercises on my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely, not at this point in my life. I've grown sedentary but going to the gym has really made me want to pursue a more healthier me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that could be the exhaustion talking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Still&lt;/em&gt;, my wife says that I seem really happy after doing it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="reviews"></category><category term="exercise"></category></entry><entry><title>The bed doesn't rock</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/03/the-bed-doesnt-rock.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-06T22:13:36-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-03-06:2012/03/the-bed-doesnt-rock.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm writing this one in bed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not the first time for that, but this time is weird. My wife and I haven't said anything beyond "Can I sleep here?" and "If you want to".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to chalk this up as a result of stress on the both of us after the contract my contract ended. Plus I have some more bad news, I didn't get a job that I really wanted after doing two interviews. I honestly felt that I was a shoe in for the position, so I'm really disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about starting some kind of video blog of my progress on how I attempt to find employment and talked about it with my friend, Nick. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing he asked me was if I had ever thought about doing a kickstarter to get a business going and what it would be. It was then, that I told him about a half thought about what I would do if I couldn't find a job. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to meet up tomorrow and talk about what things we can do moving forward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Working out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, I start working out at intence fitness and I'm a little worried about how it is going to turn out. I haven't been to the gym in years and this is promising to be a unique experence. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going because I have a one month voucher, but I don't know if I'll be staying because... well, I don't have a job. Plus the place doesn't seem to be that proffesional. I called them twice on Monday and didn't get a call back until 4pm that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll see.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="relationships"></category><category term="fitness"></category></entry><entry><title>auto repair</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/03/auto-repair.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-05T22:34:46-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-03-05:2012/03/auto-repair.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm not a fan of automotive repair. My first memorys of doing it was me attempting to help my dad work on something on the car. He'd be under there sweating and grunting as he changed the oil and then ask me to go and fetch something from his usually  disorganized&lt;sup id="fnref:disorganized"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:disorganized" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; workbench. Unfortunately, it seemed like no matter how quick I was it wasn't quick enough or the part was exactly what he wanted. I understand that it could be frustrating to wait underneath a car in the middle of the summer, but you'd think you'd be a little more prepared (i.e. have the tools ready) for a job that you've done every month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I don't want to sound ungrateful that my dad wanted make sure that I had some of the basic man skills, because there have been more than a couple times that I've had to change a tire, jump start a car or countless other little things that have popped up over the years. The only drawback is that working on cars with my dad has really left a bad impression on me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I don't like it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cringe when it comes down to the maintenance of it all. I'm willfully and woefully ignorant with it comes to anything beyond the basic maintance. I cry a little bit inside everytime that I have to bring my car into a maintenance shop. When I'm with my other no-car people friends, we complain that there aren't any honest mechanics out there that we can trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, I've run into a few who are honest, but they tend to either lose there job (drinking, divorce) or no longer able to work on it (it's complicated). It's shortly after those times that I wish I had taken a class or two on automotive repair. Not only to stop myself from getting ripped off, but to show my dad that I could do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But maybe that's a different issue all together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:disorganized"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad had a workbench in the garage that he constantly was adding and re-arranging tools on. It was one of those "I know exactly where everything is and if you couldn't find it, someone else must have moved it". After a while, we all learned that this wasn't always the case.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:disorganized" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="cars"></category></entry><entry><title>A short review of GTD and Me</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/03/a-short-review-of-gtd-and-me.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-04T21:23:51-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-03-04:2012/03/a-short-review-of-gtd-and-me.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I first heard about GTD around 2005, I had just finished school and found myself wondering what I was going to do with my life. I was living paycheck to paycheck not because of financial hardship but because I couldn't imagine life outside of the current moment. For me, GTD was blessing because it got thoughts off my mind and put them on a list somewhere...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem at that the time that my list was definitely not a trusted system and I found myself looking for more and more productivity porn to help manage my prioritize. All of this just amounted to me just moving things around on my plate and it certainly did not get me started on the oh so important habit of reviewing what I put on to the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that the underlining reason I didn't work for me was that I was avoiding a task that every adult needs to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grow up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn't on the list exactly, but in a way accomplishing things on the list would symbolize that I was leaving the "carefree" world of "come what may" for the complicated world of "come this time next month I should do A though O".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was hard, but I've grown and I look forward to taking responsibility and the list has turned into lists with different meanings and I understand the real importance of what GTD does. It heps you realize what is important to you so that you can have an idea of what you shoud be doing and in that find out who you are.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="GTD"></category></entry><entry><title>connections</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/03/connections.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-03T20:32:55-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-03-03:2012/03/connections.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don't really know why I find relationships to be difficult sometimes. I think it is because of the way that I see the world. When I was younger, it felt like I was an outsider looking in. I could almost see the connections between people as threads and see how what one person could effect another. I remember feeling alone in this because none of the connections to me seemed to be that strong. I made a conscience decision to focus more on being in the world instead of just looking at it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that I've made some really good connections with other people, but I don't know if I ever forgot the feeling and viewpoint of looking at the world in that way. There is a part of me that looks at the way people treat each other and says, "No matter what I say, that person is going to treat that other person like shit". But maybe that's all part of growing up; seeing that we can't change everybody and that being able to recognize that people must make their own decisions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have a wife and kids, I find myself dreading going back to that outlook with them. Sometimes, I feel that I'm only watching them as opposed to living with them. I've been making more time for those I love to tell them that I love them and that I'm proud of them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because, they are the most prized connections that I have.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="relationships"></category></entry><entry><title>doubts and a plan</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/03/doubts-and-a-plan.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-02T23:21:11-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-03-02:2012/03/doubts-and-a-plan.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is the second day that I've been without a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it's due to the end of the contract, I still feel kind of lost. That was my first contract, and it's weird to look back and think that even though I knew it was going to end... it still ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, if you had asked me last week whether or not I was feeling confident about what my next step was going to be, I'd tell you that I'm walking forward to the next phase in my career, but --thanks to a lot of little doubts placed by those closest to me-- I no longer feel so warm and fuzzy inside. I constantly hear "It's hard out there", "What's your plan?" and even the contractor who is replacing me was out of work for a year before he found something&lt;sup id="fnref:something"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:something" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Which has caused me to stay up tonight to write this down, get it out of my system and onto my &lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/hypercritical/56"&gt;filesystem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The fear&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fear is that I won't find some kind of employment soon. In my mind, I have constant questions floating around. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if I could never find someone to hire me again?&lt;br /&gt;
What would I do to make income?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parent in me jumps up and screams "I'd do anything to make sure that my family is happy and well taken care of", but I can't feed a family on good intentions and I'm not the kind of person to go out and rob others. Although, I have started looking around the house for things that we can sell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan or desire at this point, is to take the next couple of days thinking about what I really would like to do if I wanted to run my own business. In case, I don't get a phone call on Monday-Tuesday, what would I like to do to bring in the money. I'm not going to fool myself that I'm going to make something over night, but I'd certainly like to spend more time on making something other than comments on other people's blog. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I want to move from wantabe to somebody in a lot of areas in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:something"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I thought the idea of being a contractor was awesome. Employers like to think of you as kind of a hired gun; you come in do the job and leave. After doing it a year and talking to the other contractors and some of the people who used to be contractors, I now think of it as being a prostitute with the old joke that you don't pay a prostitute for sex, you pay them to leave. A lot of people seem ok with the idea that we are hired with the idea of being replaced and with the economy and globalization being what it is, I can't find too much fault with companies doing that.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:something" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="fear"></category><category term="employment"></category><category term="planning"></category></entry><entry><title>Post Interview Jitters</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/02/post-interview-jitters.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-27T22:10:38-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-02-27:2012/02/post-interview-jitters.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to lie. I'm nervous. Today, I had an interview and it was really very difficult for me to express myself in the most positive light. The guy kept asking me questions about where I stood as far as the support structure at my last place of employment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It really brought all those old feeling all over again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did I do wrong?&lt;br /&gt;
Why did this happen to me?&lt;br /&gt;
Where am I going?
Who am I now that I can't provide for my family?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all that I tried to find the best answers for the problems and finally I said that if they truly wanted to know how I was as a worker they can contact some of my references. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife says that was a good answer and I honestly believe her because the guy stopped asking questions after that and we moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Last Days&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was also the beginning of the last week working at Intel and -to tell the truth- the last month has been really difficult for me. In addition to the stress and worry of finding another source of employment, I've had to spend all of this month training the person who will be replacing me. Honestly, I've been trying to get him up and running but he's been running into a number of problems related to permissions and other little gotchas along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish him the best and I see a lot of new and exciting opportunities for him going forward.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="employement"></category></entry><entry><title>New Opportunities</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/02/new-opportunities.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-21T19:30:54-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-02-21:2012/02/new-opportunities.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, I got a phone call for a job interview on Thursday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's certainly better to have something going for me in that regard, I've been having trouble focusing on what my next step in life is going to be and was in danger of just freezing up. I feel that even if I don't get a job the fact that I'm going to have an interview makes me feel confident to go out and put my rsum in all kinds of places that I didn't think to put them before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going back to the point about a finding a new job, the position actually sounds like my old position at Unify and I'm hoping to do it again in a company that isn't going to treat me and the customers like resources that should be exploited until they are squeezed to death. I think the one thing that I look forward to this that I would be helping people with their problems which something that I truly enjoy. One thing that I want to look at is learning more of the back end when it comes to these kinds of systems. The last time, I relied on development to work out the details on connecting the front end to the different databases, which was the wrong decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Working out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that I've been thinking about for the last couple of days is how I'd start working out. Currently, most of my time is spent working or driving my daughters to various activities. But life is better when I work out, I wonder if I should just wake up earlier.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="jobs"></category><category term="exercise"></category></entry><entry><title>Ice and jobs</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/02/ice-and-jobs.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-20T22:33:13-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-02-20:2012/02/ice-and-jobs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, I'm thinking about doing my push up challenge again. The push up challenge has been something that I've done many times over the last three years to start off a work out routine and I've always liked the quick results it gives me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the girls to see the Disney on Ice show today and it was equally enjoyable to see the show and to have the girls watch it. They both were on the edge of their seats as they watched the Toy Story 3 characters run around and try to save the day. I wonder when my children will understand some of the bigger plot lines from the movie, because it's kind of deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the prices for things at those things are crazy. I understand that as parents, we all want to give our children the best but don't think the best things in life are $12 stale pop corn and 15 dollar iceess that come in mugs with buzz lightyears face. What kind of leasson are we teaching out children when we spend 20 dollars on something that has a value sooo much less than that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On the job front&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still no calls, and it looks like I'm going to have a harsh road ahead. I feel that this is partially my fault for trusting that I'd have something at the end of all this. I worked hard, but in the end it leads to nothing because I'm worried about what will happen next week. I know a lot of people worry like I do, but it doesn't make it better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not in the slightest...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="kids"></category><category term="jobs"></category><category term="worry"></category></entry><entry><title>The writing bug</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/02/the-writing-bug.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-19T12:12:34-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-02-19:2012/02/the-writing-bug.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, I challenged myself to write 250 words every day and although some days were harder than others, I found myself enjoying it and going over the required minimum. I really enjoyed making the transition for having a ton of words running around my head to having them placed into something that I can review and format&lt;sup id="fnref:formatting_stress"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:formatting_stress" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. For most of my life, I've been a little bit of a perfectionist and sometimes the words that I want to say don't quite measure up to the standards I'd like. This whole thing, although only weeks old has been rewarding as a way to become better at writing and allowing me to get past my own hang ups on writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I got sick about a week ago and had to take a little bit of break in order to focus on not throwing up followed shortly by a scramble to look for another job because my contract at Intel is going to expire soon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, the writing bug has bit me and I don't want to deny it any longer. I enjoy journaling because it allows me to get my thoughts together and think about what my plans are going to be moving forward. I hope that who ever reads this in the future and learn something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:formatting_stress"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That isn't to say I didn't stress out about the best way to store all these snippets that I've built up, but it was nice to put most of that aside and just work on my thoughts and getting things out of my head.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:formatting_stress" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="writing"></category><category term="jobs"></category></entry><entry><title>Feeling sick</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/02/feeling-sick.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-11T23:59:02-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-02-11:2012/02/feeling-sick.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm feeling sick. All I want to do is go to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="sick"></category></entry><entry><title>Eyes on the dance</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/02/eyes-on-the-dance.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-10T23:59:59-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-02-10:2012/02/eyes-on-the-dance.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was another great day for dancing. I went to the lindy hop lesson again and I think I did pretty good on most of the drills except for the lindy circle and I rediscovered that I have a small issue where I pull a follow out of their anchor step. It's weird to be reminded that there is a little "and" before you start dancing. I met a couple good people during the dance and it was great meeting people who dance for the sheer enjoyment of it versus trying to meet people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I've matured quite a bit because I didn't get stuck in my own head and compare myself against every other dancer including what I imagined what I was able to do during my "glory days". I just took it as a chance to have fun and work on my basic&lt;sup id="fnref:basic_dance"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:basic_dance" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The eyes have it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My daughter has a bug bite on her eye and it's swollen up pretty bad. Today, after I picked her up, she told me about how all the kids were asking about it. I don't know exactly how she felt, so I tried to let her know that she'll be alright and that the other kids just wanted to make sure that she was alright. Luckily, the eye is getting better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:basic_dance"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honestly feel that a follow would rather have a great experience doing basic moves then a lousy one with lots of moves that drive her crazy. That isn't to say a follower won't enjoy a good turn or two.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:basic_dance" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="dance"></category><category term="kids"></category></entry><entry><title>Star Wars and Hooky</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/02/star-wars-and-hooky.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-09T23:33:12-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-02-09:2012/02/star-wars-and-hooky.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, I stayed home with my oldest. She had woken up with a very pink and very swollen right eye. We didn't know if it was pink eye or something else so we had her stay home and then we took her to the doctor later in the morning. It was pretty nice spending time with her during the day because although the eye looked pretty bad, it didn't really hurt her too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She seemed to really enjoy the day that we had together and I even thought about taking her to work tomorrow if her eye doesn't get better. I think it would be nice for her to see where daddy works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Playing Hooky&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that I'm not in the office, work still comes in. Normally, this isn't a problem because I would connect to all of my necessary machines remotely ad do the work without having to deal with lag. Things have changed because I've since given away those machines to the guy I'm training to replace me. File transfers are horrible and the performance of the machine is terribly slow when I'm attempting to make a video, run a test or just check my email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Star Wars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last week or so, I've been trying to get the girls to sit down and watch Star Wars with me. Apparently, they do not have the patience to learn about a galaxy far, far away... They ask to watch it, but 30 minutes into it they fall asleep or go off and play. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="kids"></category><category term="movies"></category></entry><entry><title>vomit</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/02/vomit.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-07T14:23:12-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-02-07:2012/02/vomit.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning, I woke up to vomit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a very long night filled with little ones who don't like sleeping in their own beds by themselves coming to invade mommy and daddy's bed, I was awakened to a desperate plea for water. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran to get the water, she took two sips and then promptly threw up...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... in the bed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... on the way to bathroom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... not in the bathroom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... but on the way out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, my wife was able to take care of her during the day. So that I could go to work and train my replacement some more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Oh, the horrors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last year, I've been busy at work attempting to get an automated tool to work as it was designed. In fact, at one point I was attempting to automate the automated tool so that everyone could benefit by not running it. Personally, I thought this was a pointless endevour. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the point of automating an automated tool? Especially when that first tool is being modified and changed on an almost daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I managed to get the system somewhat working but I found myself having to do a significant amount of working trying to fix other issues and it kind of died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the problems still persist. I welcome automation, but I have to question the logic when were are stacking issues upon issues like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improvements in writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been doing this 250 word thing for almost 3 weeks now and I haven't done any editing on entries that I make. The original goal of this project was to get my thoughts out of my head and have something to look at as an achievement. I'm currently debating on whether I should read them because the process might make me too self conscience to write more.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="kids"></category><category term="writing"></category><category term="work"></category></entry><entry><title>funderland</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/02/funderland.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-05T10:34:23-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-02-05:2012/02/funderland.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was a great day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truly great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The family went to funderland and had a wonderful time going on the little rides. It's at these times that I really realize that time isn't going to stand still. Already, some of the rides are too small for my oldest and I worry that the simple things in life won't be enough to entertain them. That doesn't mean they'll want to go bungie jumping next year, but it could certainly make things different if they would rather sit at home and play video games then spend some time at the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, my oldest has been wanting to play the game &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cootie_(game)" title="Not the one where you pretend a the opposite sex is yucky, but I'll take that too!"&gt;Cooties&lt;/a&gt; and it's been fun interacting with her. I think I've mentioned that I have trouble sometimes interacting with her and I want to spend as many chances as I can to let my children know who I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dance Shape&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife and I have made up after a couple days of quite rioting and we've both decided that I needed more ways of reducing stress. So, I'll be going dancing on a more regular basis &lt;sup id="fnref:trial_basis"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:trial_basis" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The thing about this is that I'm starting over. When I'm on the floor it feels like I've never danced before. All I can remember is how to keep my hands in the right spot (so I don't get slapped) and how to keep rhythm. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every dance, I'm winded and I feel muscles that haven't been used in years burn with awakening. It hurts me physically, but my pride is swelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:trial_basis"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaning the next couple fridays or ...&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:trial_basis" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="kids"></category><category term="dance"></category></entry><entry><title>Cleaning up</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/02/cleaning-up.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-04T21:34:42-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-02-04:2012/02/cleaning-up.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, management for our complex sent out an email to all the residents that people should be cleaning up after their pets. What's the deal people? I think that if you decide to have a pet you must understand that you have a responsibility to not only feed and clean it but to clean up after it. Another thing that sucks is that I just got a dog so when I walk by my neighbors I get te stink eye because I'm going to be grouped up with the other dog owners who leave the little surprises everywhere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I need to come up with a way to relax&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping that this journaling thing would help me relax, but since I made a commitment of writing 250 everyday, it can be difficult on some days to come up with something to write and the stress of trying to think of something in the last moment has been somewhat stressful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the last couple of weeks of employment come up, I've been increasingly stressed out about it and I think I'm transfering some of those negative emotions into my marriage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is it not fair and will only cause more problems, but it does nothing to reduce the initial problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dance, Baby, Dance!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it looks like, I've been given the OK to go dancing again next week by the wife. She's kind of the jeolous type, but -aparently- I've been so stressed that she'd rather have me go out and blow off some steam then have me brooding at home.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dance"></category><category term="stress"></category></entry><entry><title>I went dancing</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/02/i-went-dancing.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-03T11:59:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-02-03:2012/02/i-went-dancing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The wife had basically kicked me out and said that I needed some time alone and she wanted some time with the girls. Up until this point, we had been in a silent one sided argument over whether or not a certain someone should wear chapstick on their lips because it causes the other party to have a split lip. So I called up my friend, Nick, and made plans for tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I was amprehensive. I haven't danced in years and I have a tendency to be very hard on myself and this sometimes gets compounded when I remember/imagine how good I used to be and look at where my skill level is now. But I got over myself and said that I was going to go enjoy myself and not critize myself too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to the dance lesson before hand and felt like I was starting off from scratch. This actually made me feel better because I could just concentrate on getting better and not think about how good it could have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Like Father, Like Daughter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I noticed about me going out dancing is that I act like my daughter when the instructor is talking. I play around, make jokes and generally lose track of the specific counts for new moves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I feel bad and correct myself too much. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I goof off again. I think it's alright because the people around me enjoy it. Sure, I don't learn that specific move very well at the time. But I feel the relaxed atmosphere makes  it easier to find the rhythem of the dance and make the total dance better than one or two moves.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dancing"></category></entry><entry><title>Two weeks</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/02/two-weeks.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-02T22:19:34-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-02-02:2012/02/two-weeks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, we have to sit back and realize that we are all only human. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a breath and just let go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Let's just Automate it&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At work, we've been talking a lot about how to make things better by automating some of the task that we do. That's great, in fact, you could argue that this one of the main functions of a computer. In stead of looking up how to spell a word, it automatically looks it up for you. In stead of mailing a check to pay your bills, you can pay it online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My problem is that a lot of the things I'm working with are wrappers around a series of other utilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Programming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man, I've been so busy with life and trying to do a million things at once that I haven't put a lot of time into my projects. In fact, the list of projects has just grown bigger and bigger the last couple of days as I have to brush up on a lot of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Writing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second week that I've been doing the 250 word project and the last couple of days have been difficult for me to come up with something to write about. Sometimes, all I can think about are short snippets like this one. I think the problem is that I haven't been keeping track of the topics that I'd like to write about thoughout the day so that when I'm home I can flesh them out.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="writing"></category></entry><entry><title>Evening Ramble</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/02/evening-ramble.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-01T10:34:23-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-02-01:2012/02/evening-ramble.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Respect is very valuable to a relationship. When we decide to trust someone with our hearts there is a rule, either spoken or commonly understood, that the two people in the relationship will respect each other as human beings. Sometimes we forget, sometimes we take each other for granted, but if you continue to disrespect your partner, you're going to have some real problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;On the Hunt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, I'm wondering how all of this is going to pan out. Time is running out...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've thought about what kind of goals I'd like to reach in the next couple of days and I think they are pretty &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S.M.A.R.T"&gt;S.M.A.R.T&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Training Others&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still training my replacement at my current job and it has definitely been a unique experience for me. To me, I see this as more evidence of our disposable culture. My employer sees me as a tool that can easily be replaced. This flies in the face of my goal of being someone that doesn't need a rsum in order to get hired. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as the company is concerned, this is standard business practice. A way to cut cost by not paying benefits and then being able to let people go without any remorse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen, if you don't like it. You don't have to work here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Project Development&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm kicking around a couple ideas at the moment and they will continue to be ideas for the foreseeable future due to some time contraints I'm under. I don't want to put anything here because that would be another commitment that I've got to think about. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll just add it to OmniFocus for now.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="random"></category></entry><entry><title>That'll fix ya!</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/thatll-fix-ya.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-31T21:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-31:2012/01/thatll-fix-ya.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My wife's sister has just had a horrible experience attempting to get her car fixed. The problem all started when she had a car accident one night&lt;sup id="fnref:car crash"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:car crash" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and the car was totaled. Others would have cut their loses then and there, but I think that because this was the first car that she bought with her own money she saw it as something worth saving&lt;sup id="fnref:saving"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:saving" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and has literally spent enough money in repairs that she probably could have bought a new one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really feel sorry for her. The world does not have an easy way of telling us wether or not something is good deal and when it comes to mechanics, even if they are honest, it doesn't mean that they know what they are doing. I've run into my fair share of people who simply want to make the most money they can from you. I've heard people say that the price for anything is "what the customer can afford". &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are we doing to each other? It seemed like "Honest work for honest pay" is a forgotten concept in our ever consumer focused world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:car crash"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was raining and she was speeding while talking on her cell phone in a sharp turn. She still says that it's not her fault.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:car crash" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:saving"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some would say that are other things that she invests her money and time into but always seem to fail her, but that's a huge bucket of flesh eating worms that I'm not even going to look at.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:saving" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="cars"></category><category term="money"></category></entry><entry><title>Training Day</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/training-day.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-30T10:02:23-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-30:2012/01/training-day.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, I met my replacement at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He's a lot older than I expected&lt;sup id="fnref:expected"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:expected" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; which got me worried. How bad is it out there to find a job?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it also got me thinking about how our disposable culture. How is it even though everyone seemed to like me at work that I'm still facing a hard end date for leaving and finding something else. I was part of the team, a reliable rock that could get things moving...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in a couple weeks, I'll be gone and that person I trained will be doing what I did for them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I don't blame the guy and &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; people have said that I should withhold some of the knowledged that I've accumulated along the way, but I won't do that because I don't need the bad karma and I'm not in the business of burning bridges. The guy is actually pretty nice and was quiet and just soaked up what I was telling him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He generally liked my teaching style&lt;sup id="fnref:teach"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:teach" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and we even had a great discussion about how development works. I spent a lot of time explaining things and it was nice to show someone all the little things that I have to do every day. I wish him the best, but I wish for better things going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:expected"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, I had an thought that whoever it was would be someone who was a handsome and good looking as I was.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:expected" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:teach"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which I find to be a great compliment. I truly enjoy teaching people things and seeing them suceed. &amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:teach" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="career"></category></entry><entry><title>What guarantee?</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/what-guarantee.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-29T22:00:05-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-29:2012/01/what-guarantee.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend, was good to me. I managed to spend sometime with my family, get some rest and look for a new job without feeling that I was cheat so other important goal. Still, I don't think that new job is going to fall into my lap, but I'm optimistic that if worse comes to worse, I can find something to keep the lights on and make sure that my family isn't hungry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in myself and I believe in the power of family. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I write it down it does sound like and affirmation, but I don't see that as a problem. What is wrong with having a positive attitude? It seems that a lot of people don't feel the need to grasps the importance of simply enjoying the moment. Like they  are saving all the happy moments for some grand retirement in the bahamas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I can tell you this now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing is guaranteed and -honestly- nothing is "deserved".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not the retirement. Not happiness. Not even that career for working your ass off in college. People change, plans change. If you haven't heard this yet, I'm sorry to busrt your bubble and be &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; guy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I was always told I was smart. I was told that I'd go far in life. I played by the rules given to me and ultimately my career has not come to fruition (just yet). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only things in this world that I have at this point in life is the love of my family and friends. It is partially for them that I'm able to get up in the morning and I'm grateful. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, it isn't guarunteed that the will be in the greatest of moods, but there is love there.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="family"></category></entry><entry><title>Sick Saturday</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/sick-saturday.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-28T22:23:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-28:2012/01/sick-saturday.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Everyone woke up late today. This is the second time in less than a week that my wife woke up before I did. Maybe I'm losing my touch, maybe I'm just that tired, my fear is that I just don't care as much. For a little more than a year, I've been getting up early to get everyone up so that we can start the day. I dress my children and get lunches ready and this is no easy task when you take into consideration that I'm trying to round up sleepy 2 and 4 year olds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It really makes me respect single mothers who have to do this all by themselves everyday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, my youngest has become more and more fussy and I'm having trouble dealing with it. I get the impression that she doesn't hear the word no from other people because that's usually what will set her off on a tantrum. Part of me thinks this has more to do with the fact that she doesn't have a lot of her own activities. As a family, we don't have a lot of time together so a significant portion of it is used to take the oldest one to her events because they don't have a lot of things for a 2 year old to do. I've been thinking about what things I can do so that she gets her own time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife and I have been watching Don Juan DiMarco for the last couple of weeks and it has really made me think about what it means to be romantic. I feel it streams from passion. It is the passion we have for each other and the passion that we have for life itself that makes romance possible.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>One week!</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/one-week.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-26T21:50:23-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-26:2012/01/one-week.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today marks the one week aniversary of my 250 words project and I have to say that I'm not only proud of what I've done but very thankful to have done it. Honestly, when you look at all the new habits that people attempt to start every year, I think this one is not only reasonably attainable but one of the most personal. Sometimes, I think about what kind of legacy I'm going to leave and wether or not my children will really know who I am as a person. Maybe they can read over some of these entries and get a better insight over who I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other personal news, I met up with my dad today and he asked that I attempt to reconnect with my brother and call my mother more. I've tried multiple time with my mom and everytime the situation gets worse. I feel that somewhere along the line we disconnected (way before I went to college) and don't know how to communicate on a deeper level then wishing each other well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My brother...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing he intentionally&lt;sup id="fnref:intention"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:intention" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; said to me was "Fuck You, Mandaris". That was on my birthday and that is where our relationship stands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, my dad also said I should go to grad school and made a compelling argument that it would help my career. I told him I'd think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:intention"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only other time was when he called my parents' place and I picked up the phone.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:intention" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="goals"></category><category term="writing"></category></entry><entry><title>Katherine Heigl, really?</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/katherine-heigl-really.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-25T13:53:04-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-25:2012/01/katherine-heigl-really.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, my wife has been listening to the Stephanie Plum audiobook series&lt;sup id="fnref:series"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:series" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and we've both been delighted to have something more to talk about other than typical parent stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I heard that they were going to make a movie out of the first book and that the trailer was already online. We even set aside some time to sit down and watch it together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're already disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't understand why people continue to give this lady movie rolls. Katherine Heigl plays the same uptight woman who "just needs to find the right one so she can relax and enjoy life (AKA get some)". For some reason she reminds me of Lisa Kudrow because I don't see her in anything else but the same role. Listen, I get it there are a lot of people who are uptight and need to relax, but I'm sure a lot of those people still have a fully working personality. Personally, I think the best thing about the trailer is that she only says a total of 4 lines in the whole thing so I'm hoping that this will be like her other movies and she'll be helped by the other actors (queue "Knocked Up").&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:series"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read the first two books a couple months before we started dating and -thanks to the power of wikipedia - I'm able to follow along when she talks about certain plot points and characters.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:series" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="movies"></category><category term="wife"></category></entry><entry><title>Hyde Doc suck</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/hyde-doc-suck.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-25T10:41:34-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-25:2012/01/hyde-doc-suck.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently came across as &lt;a href="http://groups.google.com/group/hyde-dev/browse_thread/thread/db9213433190487f" title="Message post from Google Groups"&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; from a goggle group that I'm part of that is centered around &lt;a href="https://github.com/hyde/hyde" title="Hyde on GitHub"&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt; which is what I'm currently using to statically generate my website/blog. The email was basically asking "What's up with the docs?" and all I can do is just shake my head in agreement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that a significant amount of these open source projects are created by people whose talent is mostly with the creation of the tools and not with the associatated docs. This leaves a lot of people in the dust because people see the end result and want to have something cool like that, but don't have the time/desire to dive into the code and learn how it works. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not because they are lazy, it because we are all busy people and sometimes we don't need to know every aspect of something to use it. For example, you don't have to be a mechanic to drive your car&lt;sup id="fnref:car"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:car" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I wish I could help this guy out because I've had similar problems with this and other projects and it can be daunting to stick your head out and ask the questions. But you have to have the &lt;a href="http://www.43folders.com/2008/12/01/courageous-sucking" title="Photography, and the Tolerance for Courageous Sucking via 43folders"&gt;courage to suck&lt;/a&gt; in order to get any better at something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:car"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... but a little more knowledged in this area can save you a ton of money.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:car" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>If you're feeling froggy</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/if-youre-feeling-froggy.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-24T16:04:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-24:2012/01/if-youre-feeling-froggy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the past, I've thought about becoming my own boss and running a small business where I make up the rules and direct my energy and focus on something that I enjoy. True, starting out, I would probably have to submit myself to the whims of whatever customers I'd potentially have, but I have a desire to have more control over my career. Not saying that people who work for others don't have that kind of control, so much as to say that I've met more than a few people who want have expressed thoughts of "why did they do this or that" at all the companies I've been at&lt;sup id="fnref:company"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:company" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I've come across a job posting for a programming position at Intel and wanted to apply for it. If I get selected for an interview and get past that there is a programming test with a catch&lt;sup id="fnref:catch"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:catch" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... &lt;em&gt;IF I FAIL&lt;/em&gt;, not only will I not get hired. I won't be able to interview with Intel again for an undefined time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I understand why Intel has done this there are a lot of people out there looking for jobs who look good on paper and may do well in an interview. How do you reduce the amount of people you have to look at if there is a chance that someone who bubbled up from the heap comes back?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is making me pause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But my final thought is, I could apply and not get the job or I could sit here and do nothing garuntee I won't get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:company"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that sometimes this is because the people running the company have a wider vision then those in the the trenches. Still, we shouldn't blindly trust that the ones steering the ship can see the reefs below.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:company" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:catch"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a little birdy.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:catch" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="employment"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Plain Texting</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/plain-texting.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-24:2012/01/plain-texting.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I'm messing around with plaintext to see how it might fit into my workflow. It seems like it moves pretty fast. I.m going to try simple note late on and see if that makes for a better experience when it comes to writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I'm leaning more towards a Dropbox based solution because that has a versioning system and that will help me... Some how?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had a great conversation with my wife about a lot of things. What I liked best about it was we weren't talking about something important but that we listen to each other. Two individuals who wanted to share their thoughts and opinions, it's something we definitely need more of because I don't want to wake up one day next to a stranger.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="writing"></category><category term="marriage"></category></entry><entry><title>Daughters and Daydreams</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/daughters-and-daydreams.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-23T22:47:29-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-23:2012/01/daughters-and-daydreams.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today we took my oldest to her karate class and it was entertaining. When she first started she would spin around and dance when the instructor was giving the lessons. I was tempted to pull her out of class until I felt she was old enough, but my wife insisted that if we just give her time and reminded me that we honestly couldn't beat the price for entertainment. I couldn't argue against it because the alternative would be to trying to find something else to do during that time and I didn't like my wife's idea of cruising through the mall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we kept going to class and I found myself getting more and more frustrated as she danced and pranced around while all the other kids tried hard to making it through the lessons. I became one of those over baring parents that you see in the movies (constantly telling my kid not to do this or that). Then one day, something happened... she asked me not to watch her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My daughter...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...didn't want me to be part of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I was upset. I mean, &lt;em&gt;I was trying to help her get it right!&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took a while to dawn on me. Was I really helping her by constantly correcting her? She's four years old, she shouldn't have to worry about being perfect. As a parent, I only get one chance to experience these things. I was forcing my own perfectionist views on my daughter and if I wasn't carefull I'd plant a seed doubt in her that would nag her for the rest of her days just like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, one day. I set her down (as best as I can) and told her that I love her and would always be proud of her. I stopped trying to "couch" her and now she asks that I come to her classes. She smiles when I tell her that I saw what she was doing in class. And most important to me, she's proud of herself.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="parenting"></category></entry><entry><title>My favorite movies (updated)</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/my-favorite-movies-updated.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-23T15:49:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-23:2012/01/my-favorite-movies-updated.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently loaned a friend of mine my copy of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phantom_of_the_paradise" title="Phantom of the Paradise on Wikipedia"&gt;Phantom of the Paradise&lt;/a&gt; with a note stating that it used to be one of my all time favorite movies. This got me questioning myself on if this was removed from being one of my favorite movies what replaced it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is a list of my favorite movies in no particular order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120609/" title="The Big Hit on IMDB"&gt;The Big Hit (1998)&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first taste of comedy/action. It introduced me to a bunch of actors that I'd be happy to see in years to come. Honestly, I knew about Marc Walberg before I ever heard of Marky Mark and I have a little bit of a man crush on Lou Diamond Phillips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0106308/" title="Army of Darkness on IMDB"&gt;Army of Darkness (1992)&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hail to the king, baby! The lines are legendary and watching it again just makes me laugh at how I thought the special effects were the greatest. It's almost like watching "The clash of the Titans" with boomsticks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0372784/" title="Batman Begins on IMDB"&gt;Batman Begins (2005)&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restarted a francise and cursed the world with a march of new superhero movies. I thought it was cool that even though it was a Batman movie, you don't see him in costume for half the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0266452/" title="Death to Smoochy"&gt;Death to Smoochy (2002)&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great film that introduced me to Edward Norton and Jon Stewart. I look at this movie and wonder why Robin Williams isn't in more movies and how come this didn't do better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0103639/" title="Aladdin on IMDB"&gt;Aladdin (1992)&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A whole new world! One of Disney's most popular male animated characters and I think the best disney soundtrack. Sure the other movies, have great songs but this one has three iconic songs that everyone in my generation can identify.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="movies"></category></entry><entry><title>It's almost 2 o'clock</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/its-almost-2-oclock.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-23T02:33:44-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-23:2012/01/its-almost-2-oclock.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's almost 2 O'clock in the morning and I'm having another one of those nights where I can't sleep and the only thing on my mind is all the things I need to do and all the things that I've done wrong. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;How am I going to do this?
Why did I do that?
If only such and such hadn&amp;#39;t happened.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It's hard for me sometimes to see some of the good things that I've done and how I'm making some progress going forward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that's part of the reason that I started doing this, so that I can get my thoughts out of my head and actually do something else. So what is on my mind?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight, I was thinking about all the people who I feel have taken advantage of me. Part of me forgives them because it is ultimately me who gives them the power over me, but other parts of me is bitter that they would go on with their life and never look back and help me with my situation. A card, a friendly email, something to acknowledge that I helped them get to where they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the world isn't like that and me waiting for that to happen is only going to turn me into a bitter old man instead of the slightly bitter person I'm turning into now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've got to stop being so jaded in my life, my daughters are looking up to me as an example of what a person is supposed to be and as an inspiration of what a man can do.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="reflection"></category></entry><entry><title>The Second Day</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/the-second-day.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-20T22:48:54-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-20:2012/01/the-second-day.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wow, the second day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is usually the time that I start having doubts about a new goal as the initial passion starts to ebb a little bit as I remember all the other missions and goals that I set out to do only to "not have any time for them" later on. I brings to mind &lt;a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/bregman/2012/01/your-problem-isnt-motivation.html" title="Your Problem Isn't Motivation"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; that I shared via twitter the other day where someone wrote about the problems that a friend was having with working out. It's not that the desire isn't there, it's the fact that their isn't much follow through&lt;sup id="fnref:pushups"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:pushups" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it's more of the habits and mindset that I have. As far as I can remember, I've been a little bit of a perfectionist and my own harsest critic. In fact, if you saw how I write on the computer you would be surprised how many times I'll write a sentence notice that one word is mistyped and then delete the entire thing all over again&lt;sup id="fnref:aside"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:aside" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;White Noise&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've recently started making a serious attempt to listen to white noise at work and I'm really liking the results. It's like the world becomes unplugged and the only thing that stops me from doing what I want is myself. I imagine that I'm in a box in front of my computer and the only I can do is write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't even think about whether my writing sucks, just the fact that I am writing &lt;em&gt;something!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;No cable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stopped using comcast a couple of months ago only to replace it with AT&amp;amp;T. Now instead of a fast connection that drops out every once and a while, we have a slow connection that can't support streaming media for more than one device at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:pushups"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still working through the &lt;a href="http://www.hundredpushups.com/"&gt;100 pushup challenge&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:pushups" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:aside"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely stopping the creative juices from flowing. In order to promote my writing, I think I'll just turn off spell check for these quick little blips.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:aside" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="writing"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>250 words a day</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/250-words-a-day.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-19T22:47:29-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-19:2012/01/250-words-a-day.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;All I want to do with this project is work on my writing. I want to be able to communicate better via my writingg. I don't plan on having this being seen by everyone and then placed on the internet, because I want to talk about anything that I want without reprisal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So right now, my number one concern is wether I'm going to be able to do this every day or what happens if i forget to do this. How would I punish myself or make up for it. Well, the first thing is to forgive myself. It takes time to start a new habit and -honestly- things happen. I might wake up late or have a lot of high priority things going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important thing is that I get myself some time to just sit back and have some positive time to think. At the moment, I feel that this is my best form of communication (even to myself). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been multiple times when I've opened a new page in my journal and said "Who am I and what do i want?". I think a lot of people have done this in one shape or another. For example, to paraphrase Merlin Mann that everytime that we procrastinate, we're forget who we are. How many times do we as humans procrastinate in a given day, week, month, year. You could argue that it's just a way to relax, but even then could you honestly say that all those moments helped you relieve stress?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think not.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="writing"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Sarah Milkins: The Scientist Princess Horse</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/sarah-milkins-the-scientist-princess-horse.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-08T22:51:23-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-08:2012/01/sarah-milkins-the-scientist-princess-horse.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I think one of the benefits of doing this project and making myself write on the computer is that I don't have as much anxiety about writing on a computer. The thoughts and words are appearing to me as fast as they would when I write on paper. In addition, thanks to applications like &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/byword/id420212497?mt=12"&gt;Byword&lt;/a&gt; that allow me to ignore all the spelling mistakes until I'm ready to correct them (if I choose to). My current work flow is to open up a new document and then just start writing until I meet the word requirements and finish my last thought. From there, I give the document a title, created date and tags then save it in a folder structure called "Chronicles" which then separates the entries by year and month. I'll probably set up some kind of folder action to just sort the files after saving, but -for now- I'm focused on the actual writing versus the tools and tech surrounding it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I spent some one on one time with my oldest daughter to just play around and have fun. I had asked her if she'd rather make cookies with me which is something that we've been doing more and more of but she seemed to really like the idea of just the two of us using our imagination&lt;sup id="fnref:imagination"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:imagination" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I did my best to keep up with all the ideas that she made up but I think my favorite one was the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah Milkins
She's a Princess Scientist horse who succeed when everyone said it was impossible&lt;sup id="fnref:impossible"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:impossible" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
She's 4-5 years old.&lt;br /&gt;
Goes to school a lot, even when she gets fussy...&lt;br /&gt;
Doesn't get fat when she gets older&lt;sup id="fnref:fat_and_old"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:fat_and_old" rel="footnote"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
There are only a few of them... But there is a lot of others and tons of information about them.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was just so exciting to see her talk about this idea and we both went to the rest of the family to share. It was one of those great moments when a parent can just sit back and enjoy the their little one's creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, we sat in front of the computer and giggled making little movies in PhotoBooth... This was a wonderful evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:imagination"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to be Cinderella and she got to be a talking horse. I hope it doesn't mean much, but the horse was looking for her family because they were too busy taking care of a new baby. If anything, it could be a sub-conscience idea bubbling to the surface because her sister has been sick for the last couple of days causing my wife and I to miss work and tend to the growing piles of vomit.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:imagination" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:impossible"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said that you couldn't be a princess and a scientist. I told her no and I'll put more effort into making sure she has enough exposure to science.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:impossible" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:fat_and_old"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know where she gets this exactly, but I have my suspicions&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:fat_and_old" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 3 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="writing"></category><category term="kids"></category><category term="ideas"></category></entry><entry><title>I'm tired of chasing</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/im-tired-of-chasing.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-06T18:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-06:2012/01/im-tired-of-chasing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been having a nagging feeling in the back of my mind for the last couple of months (if not years) about the whole social media thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, it was the coolest thing having something like myspace to allow me to keep in touch with my friends by sharing pictures, comments and images. It allowed everyone to have a presence on the internet without having to think about setting up (or paying for) ways to connect. As an added bonus, you could personalize the your profile page to reflect your style and interests&lt;sup id="fnref:style"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:style" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I should have known that it wasn't going to last. The sight as a whole became filled with people who seemed to love showing off their animated gif collection and increasing the magic number next to "friends". One time, I got an invitation from my then roommate's sister who I had never met in life simply because she wanted to make it to 400 before her one of her friends. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook was a breath of fresh air at some point, and it clean, simple and uncustomizable (at the time) interface really drew me in. This was before everyone had a problem with privacy and honestly, I had taken enough cs classes and seen enough movies and tv shows to know that I really shouldn't put anything on there that I wouldn't want Moe Lester to look at. Once again, I was happy to connect with all my friends and see how life was treating them, but it wasn't long before I experienced the same issues of attracting friends who weren't really friends and having a hug stream of information and distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was at this point, that I started to realize that despite all the time and effort spent maintaining a connection with all my online friends, I felt that I was still missing out on that human connection with those I cared about. The desire to have a long discussion was replace by the desire to have people respond. In order to promote a response or get feed back quicker, I found myself editing myself for lenght or watering down the content to make it less controversal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I continued and started following my friends on twitter. Not only could I get their quips and links, but I was also able to discover other people I found interesting. I had basically let my facebook account just rot away and really enjoyed how twitter brought the information to me instead of me having to chase it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then google+ came out and all of the real life friends I was talking to started using that. The only updates that I see from people I've met in real life are from people doing checkin from 4square&lt;sup id="fnref:4square"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:4square" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and I seriously doubt the people I follow can pick me out from their hordes of followers (not that I blame them, I don't have a lot of characteristics that stick out on the web).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google, the behemeth that keeps getting bigger and bigger. I'm not arguing that the best of breed should go to the top, but I will say that I'm tired of generating content for other people just so that it can disappear without a trace. I'm tired of spending time working on a connection that really isn't there. I'm more than a node that connects two (or more) points. I find that my voice is just justification that the larger systems (myspace, facebook, google+) should be used in order to contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How social are we when we trade our individual voice to be part of the chorus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to be "social" then go ahead, but if you want to find me. I'll be here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:style"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember sites dedicated to selling themes and other dedicated to showing nothing but the worst offenders of "good taste". What I also remember is that people were constantly putting up huge pictures and videos that killed your bandwidth. Good times!&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:style" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:4square"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, does the Library of Congress need record the fact that you were the mayor of burger town for a month straight?&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:4square" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="social"></category></entry><entry><title>I'd like to work on something cool</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/01/id-like-to-work-on-something-cool.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-01-05:2012/01/id-like-to-work-on-something-cool.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;That's what I've been telling myself for a couple years now, and it seems like I'm only giving it lip service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem (other than follow through) is finding something cool to work on. It is sooo much easier to look at what I &lt;em&gt;don't&lt;/em&gt; want to work on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I went back to school to get some more 'learnin' and it was actually a lot of fun after the initial issues not having been in a class room since 2004. The [professor][chang] was not only knowledgable but actually cared about teaching understanding. For a second, I even thought about going back to school so that I could teach as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important thing about it was that I really got back into the passion of programming. I enjoyed completing the assignments and working with a group of people towards a common goal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is what I want to do.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>My favorite movies</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2011/12/my-favorite-movies.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2011-12-20:2011/12/my-favorite-movies.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently loaned a friend of mine my copy of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phantom_of_the_paradise"&gt;Phantom of the Paradise&lt;/a&gt; with a note stating that it used to be one of my all time favorite movies. This got me questioning myself on if this was removed from being one of my favorite movies what replaced it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is a list of my favorite movies in no particular order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Hit&lt;br /&gt;
This was my first taste of comedy/action. It introduced me to a bunch of actors that I'd be happy to see in years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Army of Darkness&lt;br /&gt;
Hail to the king, baby!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Batman Begins&lt;br /&gt;
Restarted a francise and curse the world with a march of new superhero movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death to Smoochy&lt;br /&gt;
This movie is great&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aladin&lt;br /&gt;
A whole new world! One of Disney's most popular male animated characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="movie"></category></entry><entry><title>I don't know anything</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2011/11/i-dont-know-anything.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-03-06T12:31:34-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2011-11-28:2011/11/i-dont-know-anything.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Isn't that the best way to start something. Just open yourself up and see what happens. I think it's better to start over if it get's you to where you want to be.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="musing"></category></entry><entry><title>What's on my mind and the current moment</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2011/10/whats-on-my-mind-and-the-current-moment.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-10-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2011-10-14:2011/10/whats-on-my-mind-and-the-current-moment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;The maps.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife wants me to pick up some maps for her presentation tomorrow. It's really important to her because she's emailed me twice and called at least once to confirm that I'm going to pick them up. Part of me wants to pick them up and pretend I was able to so that I can surprise her later tonight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won't because it's not right. I wouldn't want her to do something like that to me and we should always treat people the way we wanted to be treated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finding the time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sometimes find myself wondering "Where did the time go?" or "When am I going to be able to do that?". But what it call comes down to is "What is important to me". &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I take the time to set a goal of 250 or 15 minutes a day or do I sit back and relax with a video game? &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Interests</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2011/10/interests.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-03-06T12:32:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2011-10-07:2011/10/interests.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I thought about Steve Jobs and how he impacted my life, I thought about how his passion for things drove him to be the person he is. Then I thought about my passions and took some time to write down some of my interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Tech Interests&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Programming on the mac&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Objective-C&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me this is more than a little sentimental. I also like the syntax as I like the idea that it takes from smalltalk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"They" say that you should know at least on scripting language. For some reason, python calls to me more than Ruby. I think it's the contriran in me that wants that doesn't want to do what everyone else is doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also Python has bindins in lldb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;lldb&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoy the theory of programming languages. My favarite classes were "programing languages" where you learned the evolution of different languages and how they differ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second was compiler theory where we built a very basic clone of the c language&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Web development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Accebility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not claimig to be a designer, but I remember the time when you had to surf the internet using a dial up modem and how it seemed to take a long time to get information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these pains of that time were sights that used real play or images for everything. There were people offering classes on how to optimize websites, because it was impossible to do anything until it loaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It got me thinking about what would happen if the pictures never loaded? How can they use it? What if I had trouble using the mouse? I have a number of friends who have asked this same question and I'm reminded of this issue everytime I try to use the computer with my kids in my lap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Semantics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the idea of specificing what things are really supposed to mean. If you look at my website now, you should be going to a clean design that easy for people to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Mac Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tons of great software on all platforms, but it seems like all my favorites are on the mac due to how well they seem to work standalone or together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Automator &amp;amp; Applescript&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I play with the idea of using these two tools more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Personal Interests&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to put my ideas into words. I sometimes imagine differn storis (such as action films and children's books) and scenerios (mostly how I would do something different or an argument with someone).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my issues is sitting down to write. I critique my writing before I even begin and then I let myself get lost in the tools of writig more than the writing itself. Currently, I'm fighting over what's the best place to keep my notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Self-improvement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I being the best me that I can be?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="goals"></category><category term="interests"></category></entry><entry><title>What does 250 words look like?</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2011/10/what-does-250-words-look-like.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-10-07T21:36:57-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2011-10-07:2011/10/what-does-250-words-look-like.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently applied to become a professional blogger for macuser.com (a blog run by macworld). As part of the application process, I was to write two articles of 250-300 words to show my qualifications as a writer. I've writen them an have since placed them on my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember feeling stressed about creating the entries. Although I like to journal my thoughts time to time. Sitting down and coming up with something for other people to read make me nervous and I had tons of questions like : "What would I write about?", "How can I make what I wrote stand out from the dozens if not hundreds of applicants?" One doubt that really got to e ws the question about how I could do something like this about three times a week and whether or not I truely wanted too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I'm not going to say i'm happy I didn't get the job because I'm not. I would love to get paidfor writing, but I don't think working for macuser at this point in time would be good for the writer in me. I want to be a good write and I feel that writing (like some many other things) needs active practice to get better. The best way to do that is want to write better (other than actually doing it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, I'm not at the level of &lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net"&gt;John Gruber&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/author/john-siracusa/"&gt;John Siracusa&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://shawnblanc.net"&gt;Shawn Blanc&lt;/a&gt;, but they weren't always who they are now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can only sit down down and write for my #1 audience and that's me.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="writing"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Put Who in the What Now?</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2011/09/put-who-in-the-what-now.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-09-05T16:10:01-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2011-09-05:2011/09/put-who-in-the-what-now.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I'm taking an Operating Systems class at Sac State and the first feeling is fear. It's been a long time since I've sat down to learn something completely different from what I've done before and I've lost track of that feeling of excitement and discovery when it comes to coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True, I do a little bit of coding for work and have kept busy by doing little example programs here and there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True, I've been attempting to get myself ready for the class by doing simple exercises with gdb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I can't shake my self doubts. I feel like I'm being followed by a huge shadow that constantly sings a chorus of "You're not good enough", "You're gonna fail", "If you were smarter, you wouldn't have to do this in the first place."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breathe... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to make it... Somehow...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>iFinance 3.3 Review</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2011/08/ifinance-33-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-08-23T10:18:12-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2011-08-23:2011/08/ifinance-33-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After Intuits announcement that they would only be supporting &lt;a href="http://www.macworld.com/article/146714/2010/02/quicken_essentials.html"&gt;Quicken Essentials&lt;/a&gt; in Lion, other mac developers were happy to ease the troubled mind of users with &lt;a href="http://www.macworld.com/article/161401/2011/08/lion_personal_finance_quicken_alternatives.html"&gt;various options&lt;/a&gt; that were designed to take advantage of some of the features of the new OS. Since the last &lt;a href="http://www.macworld.com/article/142864/2009/09/ifinance3.html"&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; of iFinance, Synium Software, the maker of &lt;a href="http://www.macworld.com/article/152202/2010/06/chronories.html"&gt;Chronories&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.macworld.com/article/58184/2007/06/macfamilytree44.html"&gt;MacFamilyTree&lt;/a&gt;, have been working hard to make version 3.3 a release that can standup in comparison with the other options. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first improved feature that you will notice is the stock tracker graph which shows the value of a stock over time and allows you mouse over to see the value of a specific day. Unfortunately, the interface is still rather simple as adding your own personal investments is a multi part process of first adding the stock, clicking on the transactions button, pressing the "+" button, putting in your information (purchase date, quantity, cost) and finally clicking around the different textfields hoping your information was saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One feature that the release boast is the ability to add more media to a particular transaction. This is great if you want to add a two part receipt, warranty, picture of you standing next to your new purchase or whatever. The problem is that when you click on the media button for that particular transaction, the one window interface becomes even more crowded as it splits the transaction panel in two. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Looks alright on my iMac, but too cluttered on my 13'" src="iFinance_media.png" title="Adding media to a transaction" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I have to say that this release maintains the 2 1/2 mouse rating it was given originally based off of the continued frustration with getting information into the application and overall user experience.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="finance"></category><category term="macosx"></category><category term="software"></category></entry><entry><title>Another look at Yahoo! Mail</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2011/08/another-look-at-yahoo-mail.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-08-23T10:14:12-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2011-08-23:2011/08/another-look-at-yahoo-mail.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, it seems like everyone is wrapped up in his/her own group of social networks. There's twitter, Facebook, google+, and even myspace; for those of you who are still looking for interesting ways to use the blink tag. The blink tag itself was part of the excitement of the internet at that time and every beginning textbook or html class had an example of how to "best" use it (Hint: Never). Another annoying aspect of being on the internet at that time were the Signatures placed in your outgoing emails. I can understand that a company wants to advertise that they provide free email, but shouldn't the fact that I sent the email via hotmail.com or yahoo.com be enough? To top it off, a lot of free email providers, at the time, where smashed by an assortment of issues like demand for more space and functionality (POP, IMAP, Address Book, etc) and the dreaded SPAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I was more than excited to get a google mail address (Does anyone else call it that?) and only logged into my old account to look at all the spam to remind me of how good I have it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, Yahoo! has slowly turned the situation around. The first thing they did was offer free IMAP and contact synchronization to iPhone users. This was great if you had an iPhone, but if you were a regular user you still had to use the web interface if you wanted to send an e-mail, unless you paid for Yahoo! Mail Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then wonders upon wonders, Yahoo opened up &lt;a href="http://www.ymailblog.com/blog/2011/07/yahoo-offers-mail-contacts-instant-messaging-and-calendar-sync-for-apples-new-osx-lion-operating-system-allows-for-unique-contacts-sync-with-macbooks/"&gt;IMAP free for everyone&lt;/a&gt; and eliminated the mountains of spam that onceI get. All without that little signature at the bottom that tells people I'm sending email from the '90s.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="review"></category><category term="yahoo"></category></entry><entry><title>My feelings about Lion</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2011/08/my-feelings-about-lion.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-08-17T10:50:12-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2011-08-17:2011/08/my-feelings-about-lion.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I consider myself a reasonable person who loves mac products. I've been using mac since the summer of 2004, when I had an internship at Apple Computer Inc. It was one of the greatest work experience of my life and I wish I had done more to pursue a career working there (but that's a whole 'nother topic). The thing is that I've used all the OS's since then and every time a new one comes out I go through a series of steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial excitement that my favorite OS is getting an update that should make it even better!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A splash of cold water as I notice that a lot of the updates are under the hood (Core&lt;Fill_in_the_blank&gt;) and all the big ticket items are basically eye candy that I don't see myself or anyone else using day to day (dashboard).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last minute concern that I haven't backed my computer up in um a while..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excitement that I'm installing the latest and greatest!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admiration that by and large the performance of the OS is better on the same hardware&lt;sup id="fnref:hardware"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:hardware" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nit pick at little changes to the user interface (what's with the ugly font and background with the notes in Mail? You can choose to colors blue or grey. What color and shape do you want your folders? That last one is a trick question.) and what not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fall in love all over again. With all the software that developers are able to make with the new OS, why would you want to go back? Learn to live with it or learn to tweak it (How? It's a secret&lt;sup id="fnref:secrets"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:secrets" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to work every day wishing that I could work on a mac.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;So what's the deal with lion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually really liked lion when I first got it. Although at first glance it looks like someone has been sucking more and more color out of it, you can tell that a lot detail went into how things looked. Mail.app has really gotten a good shining and I was pleasantly surprised/creeped out to see how safari was smart enough to see that I was logging into my old yahoo account and then set it up in mail with only a couple button clicks. The key thing about the whole process is that it's really smooth and -for the most part- you wouldn't know that a whole lot of things have changed and if you ask me a couple months from now I probably wouldn't want to go back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with most changes, there are somethings that I don't like about lion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where are the scrollbars?&lt;br /&gt;
I know I'm not the only one out there who misses them. I was concerned about this since they demoed it during the WWDC keynote. I understand that they are supposed to flash when you first load the page or some kind of change happens, but I think that disappearing scrollbars are pointless when I'm using it at home on my iMac. In fact, I feel that they work against the user in some circumstances. For example, when I'm in Mail.app and I'm looking at the list of messages, I shouldn't have to look at the number of message at the top to figure out that I should scroll down to get more.
&lt;img alt="Problem with mail Lion mail.app" src="problem_with_lion_mail.png" /&gt;
When you do enable the scrollbars, they have a tendency to look kinda bland. I like to imagine them as grey tear drops that are sad that they have to be there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As natural as a gesture&lt;br /&gt;
I understand that this point and the last could probably be a non-issue if I only had a magic trackpad or used the new OS with a laptop like they did with WWDC keynote demo. But, I don't have one. I have a 4+ button mouse that I use instead of the magic mouse that used to hurt my hand after an hour or so (great reason to enjoy more family time). I know I could probably get used to it if I wanted to, but this is my family's home computer. My wife and I have to work all day and use our windows boxes. This is not a strong argument, "Hey baby, I know that you've had a long day at work typing and whatnot and you want to use the machine that helped pay for to relax and check on that book of faces and electronic mail thing the kids are all into, but do you mind re-wiring your brain to make up down and down up because I don't want to go into preferences to change it back to what you are accustomed to".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rum-rum-resume&lt;br /&gt;
It is at this point that I feel a lot of people might disagree with me. I wish the resume feature of the OS was a little better fined tuned. As in, I wish I could turn it off. What? You love the fact that you can start exactly where you left off in a program? You know what? So do I! Does my wife like seeing all the safari windows that I had up when I was on there last&lt;sup id="fnref:last"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:last" rel="footnote"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;? Do I like waiting an extra couple minutes while &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the applications that I had open before I restarted the machine start back up and restore themselves to their previous state all at once? No. 
Some would argue that I could simply hold down the option button when I close a program to stop this behavior and that it does help in a lot of ways. I don't dispute this, but I do feel that there should be more control over this. If you have a faster machine (like something with a solid state drive), then you wouldn't have a problem with this. But it is a reminder to me that OS didn't have this feature before because of the overhead associated with it. I know that a year or so from now it will be a non-issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The witches brew&lt;br /&gt;
This last part is purely a geek pet peeve for me, because this doesn't affect anyone other than developers. I use a couple of software packages to create this site and play with my pipe dream of being a cocoa programmer. One of the tools that I use is homebrew. &lt;a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/"&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; is a package manager that downloads the source code of other software (ex. MySQL, Node.js), compiles them and install them in a way that doesn't cause your system to fall to pieces. The problem is that the new OS uses a different default compiler and has changed the permissions on some of the folders. I could change the compiler back, but I didn't want to mess around with it too much. The machine that I have lion installed on is my family computer and I don't want my wife to kill me when I need to re-install for the third time to fix something that I didn't understand fully. It probably already fixed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I really like lion and I look forward to seeing what developers can do with the new technology going forward. Does it have some faults? Yes, but with any healthy relationship you have to understand that OS change over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:hardware"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course there is a little slow down when loading dashboard for the first time and the little bit of slow down when spotlight is indexing everything, but after that you wouldn't know unless you were already hurting for resources. &amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:hardware" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:secrets"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually don't use secrets. I used to do a lot of re-installs so I just change a couple preferences and leave it as is. The only thing that I know use that would be considered a tweak would be LauchBar. &amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:secrets" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:last"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoils the surprise trip to Fry's!&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:last" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 3 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="OSX"></category><category term="macosx"></category><category term="lion"></category></entry><entry><title>It's just how I feel about the subject</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2011/03/its-just-how-i-feel-about-the-subject.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-03-10T20:52:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2011-03-10:2011/03/its-just-how-i-feel-about-the-subject.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Don't get me wrong, I love a good book, but it seems like a lot of my teachers where focused on adding more words to simple meanings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.smbc-comics.com/index.php?db=comics&amp;amp;id=2112#comic"&gt;&lt;img alt="Require Reading" src="saturday_morning_breakfast_cereal_20110102.gif" title="Why do they hate reading?" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="comics"></category></entry><entry><title>Another day</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2011/02/another-day.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-02-06T10:11:12-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2011-02-06:2011/02/another-day.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, World.&lt;br /&gt;
I'm alive for another year. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Looking back</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2011/01/looking-back.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-06T07:15:31-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2011-01-06:2011/01/looking-back.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm just a guy trying to make the best of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category><category term="review"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting back into it</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2011/01/getting-back-into-it.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-05T23:06:58-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2011-01-05:2011/01/getting-back-into-it.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, the last couple of weeks have been really busy in between moving to a new location, new routines, new expenses and just a lot of new things. Unfortunately, I've allowed myself to get off the routines that I've been putting together and the biggest reason is my own procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of me wants to make this blog "Perfect", so I spend too much time thinking about all the little tools I should use to make it. I wonder "How am I going to host images?", "Am I going to continue hosting it on google?", "How do I keep track of old post: Should I leave them on the server or on my local machine?", "What if my laptop gets stolen?", "Should I only write on my laptop or anything I get my hands on?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It goes on and on, and I forget the important thing. This blog is for me. I do it to put my thoughts into words and from there I post it for the whole world to see. I make it, not the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't like it, you don't have to read it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>The New Digs</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2011/01/the-new-digs.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-03T19:57:42-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2011-01-03:2011/01/the-new-digs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, I'm in the process of moving in. The goal? To own everything I make. I don't expect many people to understand, but then again...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="website"></category></entry><entry><title>What do you do when all you want to do is write...</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/12/what-do-you-do-when-all-you-want-to-do-is-write.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-12-08T20:13:55-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-12-08:2010/12/what-do-you-do-when-all-you-want-to-do-is-write.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;... you just start writing...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="writing"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Productivity Dash</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/11/productivity-dash.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-11-24T22:38:29-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-11-24:2010/11/productivity-dash.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've got a lot to do...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all do, it's important to remember what you priorities are. Do I really want to put the time into something that isn't going to move my life forward?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="observation"></category></entry><entry><title>Going forward...</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/11/going-forward.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-11-13T23:11:12-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-11-13:2010/11/going-forward.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, a lot of things have happened in the last couple months and I honestly don't know where to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm just hoping that you, the internet, can be patient as I attempt to put all of this together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything, this is going to be a great ride.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="observation"></category></entry><entry><title>Creating New Website</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/06/creating-new-website.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-06-03T18:05:37-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-06-03:2010/06/creating-new-website.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Despite all of my &lt;em&gt;hard work&lt;/em&gt; on facebook, it's time that I also have some kind of static site as well.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="website"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry><entry><title>Email to Andy Ihnatko</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/05/email-to-andy-ihnatko.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-05-27T23:44:20-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-05-27:2010/05/email-to-andy-ihnatko.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently sent an email to Andy Ihnatko, a really cool journalist from the Chicago Sun Times and Macbreak Weekly. I thought it was pretty good and I'd like to post it to you the internet!
(Note: I didn't take the time to do a second draft this is all from the top of my head).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello Andy, I'm a fan and a happy mac user. I've heard a lot of arguments that I've paid too much for my mac, but I can't think of a time when I had to worry about this or that not working. Anyway, you've probably heard and experienced this story yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of me emailing is that I'm having a hard time arguing with my co-workers in regards to the iPhone. I got one and I love it, the thing is testimate to modern computing and we wouldn't even be having a discussion about "smart" or "feature" phones if it hadn't come to pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems to me, that a lot of the talk after google IO were complaints against Apple not being open and that the web wanted to be free, but it seems that no one brings up the fact that the very first applications that third party developers could put on the iPhone were &lt;em&gt;gasp&lt;/em&gt; web apps that: 1) Free to develop 2) Free of censorship from apple 3) Freely available to everyone and can run on (basically) any webkit based browser&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can understand some of the frustration that some of the developers are experiencing when it comes for submitting there application, but it seems kind of silly when somebody complains that she or he can't use tool Z on product i so they want to have nothing to do with it (or cancel a national conference).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, I'm reminded of someone saying they want to run their playstation games on a nintendo, but then I look at the people who are actively complaining and I wonder how many of them are console gamers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other thing, I'm tempted to buy the playboy application and do a little blog post about it, because I keep Leo talking about how apple is being hypocritical on their porn policy. I don't think this is true, because the applications that were taken off the store all contain nudity. The description on the playboy application says that it doesn't explicitly. The only thing is that I'm afraid my wife might beat me if she sees it when she syncs here ipod touch, but I think I could get away with it if a respected journalist said I should in order to get the inside scoop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I'd like to thank you for doing what you do. You explain your arguments a lot better than I do and it comes across and solid reasoning. I hope that you've read this and smiled!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salutations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><category term="OSX"></category><category term="email"></category><category term="celebrities"></category></entry><entry><title>Photography, and the Tolerance for Courageous Sucking</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/05/photography-and-the-tolerance-for-courageous-sucking.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-05-25T20:30:46-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-05-25:2010/05/photography-and-the-tolerance-for-courageous-sucking.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Merlin Man has a great piece about the most important thing about &lt;a href="http://www.43folders.com/2008/12/01/courageous-sucking"&gt;starting something&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardest part of starting over is swallowing my pride, saying that I need help and then starting up again.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting back to work</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/05/getting-back-to-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-05-24T23:57:28-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-05-24:2010/05/getting-back-to-work.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, things have been hectic and I'm thinking about a lot of things in my personal life. The key is that those near me are happy and doing well. Living, learning and enjoying life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I could say that about people outside of my house, but I can only do so much.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Good for him</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/05/good-for-him.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-05-01T07:58:06-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-05-01:2010/05/good-for-him.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My brother is engaged to get married. I'm happy that he's found someone.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Late night oil</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/04/late-night-oil.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-04-16T12:18:25-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-04-16:2010/04/late-night-oil.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I'm up late again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's weird being up this late. Just sitting here thinking about what I could be doing instead of doing it. It's a quite moment where I can tune out for a couple minutes and just here the humming of the lightbulbs and tell myself, "It's ok to slow down and take this minute for me"&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="observation"></category></entry><entry><title>Blogging, bloggin, bloggin...</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/04/blogging-bloggin-bloggin.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-04-07T23:34:59-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-04-07:2010/04/blogging-bloggin-bloggin.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I really do love blogging, even if most of it is junk!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="observation"></category></entry><entry><title>Adults</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/04/adults.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-04-01T23:32:37-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-04-01:2010/04/adults.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been thinking a lot about what it means to be an adult. To me, being an adult means owning up to your responsibilities and making reasonably rational decisions. I say reasonably because there are things that can't/shouldn't be rationalized. For example, love between exact opposites or why they stopped showing Captain Eo at DisneyLand (completely irrational).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the opposite side of the equation, we have emotion. The western world has a love/hate relationship with emotions. In America, it is written that we should all be working on that constant pursuit for happiness. Some of the best movies are about people who do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an adult, we all have to balance this.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="relationships"></category></entry><entry><title>I love my Wify</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/03/i-love-my-wify.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-28T12:08:03-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-03-28:2010/03/i-love-my-wify.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love my drama-free (most of the time) wife. Thank you baby momma.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="wife"></category></entry><entry><title>I couldn't sleep</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/03/i-couldnt-sleep.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-19T01:46:06-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-03-19:2010/03/i-couldnt-sleep.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After watching the movie Everybodys fine, a nice movie about a newly widowed father who travels across the country to meet up with his children who he has a strained relationship with. It got me thinking about my own relationships. Have I done everything I could do? If I were to die would the people who matter to me go forward with their lives knowing that I wished them well? Would my children know that all I truly want for them is to live a full and happy life? Did I really live life to the fullest and lead by example?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last one, Im going to say no and yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dont live every moment to the fullest, in fact, I have caught myself drifting in and out a couple times. Like the song from Linkin Park, Its easier to run, I find that Ive got a certain part of myself that just zones out sometimes. That says Hey, I dont think I can change this situation so why fight it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, its horrible, but I think its how most people are living there life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also think thats why people cheat on their spouses and just treat people like shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Im tired of it. Really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im tired of being told to live in a little box, and Im tired of being told to shhhh and keep quiet about things for the stupidest of reasons. That, in the end, come back to ultimately bite me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I feel that a lot of people are just set in their ways. I could tell a certain someone that I love them a hundred times and they would only look back to a time I didnt return their phone call because I was changing a diaper and say that Im a liar. I could tell someone that they should stand up make a change to some kind of product and that person could say Hey, my hands are tied because the boss gave me these things to do. I could hug someone and they would only say that Im only doing it because its expected and not because I want to become closer to them and I may never be able to do it again. I could take someones keys to make sure they dont drink and drive, but that person would only see me as attempting to belittle them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a certain point, Ive got to say Listen, Im an adult and youre an adult. Im going to go this way. You can do whatever you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im going to stop there because I have to be at work in 5 hours.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>We are outta here!</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/02/we-are-outta-here.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-28T20:30:31-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-02-28:2010/02/we-are-outta-here.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've moved!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="milestone"></category></entry><entry><title>Review (February 18th, 2010)</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/02/review-february-18th-2010.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-18T21:44:51-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-02-18:2010/02/review-february-18th-2010.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ive been pushed off of my review wagon (again). One thing you have to keep in mind when starting a new habit is that you should forgive yourself if you miss a day and get back to it as soon as you can. Well, things have been busy in my life: My dad had a stroke, Im going to be moving to a new place at the end of the month, Ive had the privilege of raising someone elses kid for a while and Ive also been re-evaluating my life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I dont know what to do or feel... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like a leaf in the wind...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal Accomplishments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Met Andy Ihnatko&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting better and better about tracking my list of things to do&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing my review again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="review"></category></entry><entry><title>I met Andy Ihnatko</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/02/i-met-andy-ihnatko.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-16T23:15:29-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-02-16:2010/02/i-met-andy-ihnatko.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I saw him speak at a macnexus meeting!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Picture of me and Andy Ihnatko" src="ihnatko.jpg" title="He seems like such a great guy" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category><category term="celebrities"></category></entry><entry><title>A penny for my thoughts</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/02/a-penny-for-my-thoughts.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-06T10:49:34-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-02-06:2010/02/a-penny-for-my-thoughts.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm trying to think of all the positive things that are happening in my life. Sometimes I lose track of those things that I should be grateful for so I want to list them here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My wife.&lt;br /&gt;
  There are no perfect people in this world, but when push comes to shove I feel that she has m back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My children.&lt;br /&gt;
It's a kind of pride and warm feeling to see them grow from little meatballs into little girls. I'm not looking forward to have them leave one day. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My job.
It's been able to support our house hold at a standard of living that's becoming harder and harder to maintain in this economy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The economic rock on which we stand&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of economy, I've been thinking about how even though we are in a recession, there seems to be more and more ads on things. Once again, I'm not a communist, but it seems crazy that our society has no problems having all these messages about buying things when most Americans are having problems balancing thier budgets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caeer builder recently had a survey stating that 42 percent of their &lt;a href="http://www.careerbuilder.com/share/aboutus/pressreleasesdetail.aspx?id=pr651&amp;amp;sd=8/11/2011&amp;amp;ed=8/11/2099"&gt;respondents&lt;/a&gt; were living paycheck to paycheck. I think it is more of a personal thing rather than the amount of money that people make. From a very young age we are taught to keep up with "the Jones'" and the other thing that we are taught about money is the single semester of econ&lt;sup id="fnref:econ_class"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:econ_class" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in high school. Personally, I think that it's a little late because by then all your classmates have already been bombarded by barbie, GI Joe and Disney and I doubt many of them have an idea of what it is costing to live like they live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:econ_class"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My econ teacher was pretty well off. Her husband made a lot of money and this was her way of giving back to society. There were many rumors about her drinking in her car between classes.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:econ_class" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="kids"></category><category term="money"></category></entry><entry><title>Review (February 5th, 2010)</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/02/review-february-5th-2010.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-05T23:34:04-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-02-05:2010/02/review-february-5th-2010.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, it seems that Ive allowed myself to get caught up in the drama again, but I feel like a much better person. I vaguely remember someone once saying that its how we deal with events that define us. I had some very interesting things happen to me since the last time I did a review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, I got sick again. This time it was really bad and I couldnt leave the bathroom for more than an hour or two before my stomach emptied itself. I dont think Ive been sick like that in years and Im seriously considering talking to my doctor about why Ive been getting sick so often. My wife says that it might be all the stress of working, a general level of dissatisfaction with where I am in my life, the relationship between me and my family, the list is long. But I definitely could be worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, pack up the kids, we are moving! We are moving to a two story townhouse that has almost twice the amount of space of our current place. Were put the deposit down and were just waiting for the credit checks and then well be set for the end of the month to move in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, I looked at the number of posts that I did in January(12) and compared it with the number of posts that I did back in 2009 (36) and 2008 (24). Wow, thats a lot of information to put on Da Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forth, I came across a journal that I used to keep up a couple years ago and -honestly- I could write a post about it alone. It was sad that I looked at it and saw that I am still dealing with issues from back then. To sum it up, its been more reason to do more in order to move my life forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal Accomplishments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wake up &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up a work journal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things on my mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to make it all better...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="review"></category></entry><entry><title>43 Folders | Time, Attention, and Creative Work</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/02/43-folders-time-attention-and-creative-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-04T15:11:45-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-02-04:2010/02/43-folders-time-attention-and-creative-work.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="What happens if you check your email every 5 minutes" src="24000.jpg" title="You waste soooo much time" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, I can't believe I spent so much time looking into productivity p0rn! I used to look at 43folders.com almost every other hour looking for that "One secret that would make me productive".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secret, just do it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="productivity"></category><category term="email"></category></entry><entry><title>Surviving with More Kids (part. 2)</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/01/surviving-with-more-kids-part-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-29T21:08:04-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-01-29:2010/01/surviving-with-more-kids-part-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, I don't want to say that the honeymoon phase is over, but I will say that things have become a lot more... hectic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess the first day had a lot going for it since I only saw them for 4 hours before it was time for them to go to bed and we were lucky to be able to take them all to the park followed by the library where they can run off a lot of energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, was different. Thankfully, my mom took the older girls out to the museum and to go eat and when they got back they had cookies and cake. I -in my infinite wisdom- then told my wife that she should go out and take a break from all the kids and although it took a lot of convincing she (although she did take our youngest which I was grateful for later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, things weren't as bad as you would think, but it wasn't perfect either. I was running around breaking up little fights over toys and turns. The kids screaming "NO! It's my turn" and running to the other side of the room because someone is doing something they shouldn't: Spilling things, taking things, eating things, thankfully not breaking things, but I'm sure something has disappeared into that magical land that missing socks go. I even attempted to go over letters with very poor results. I could tell that the oldest one was frustrated, but I hope that I'll be able to get her to recognize most of the alphabet before she leaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the girls settled and I managed to get them all into bed without the same hassle as the night before. Although, I did have one call me a dozen times for various things until I put my foot down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing of note was although our guest don't seem to get along during the day, the oldest one does show some concern for her sister. I feel sad for them because with all the drama that they've gone through the only one's they truly have is each other. To wrap it up, this time I got to sleep in the bed and had to share it with my oldest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She threw up on me twice.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="parenting"></category></entry><entry><title>My new addition</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/01/my-new-addition.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-28T21:38:50-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-01-28:2010/01/my-new-addition.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Isn't she cute!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="A picture of Alex" src="alex_mia.jpg" title="A picture of Alex" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="parenting"></category></entry><entry><title>Surviving with More Kids (part. 1)</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/01/surviving-with-more-kids-part-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-28T08:22:04-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-01-28:2010/01/surviving-with-more-kids-part-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, after a particularly long series of events. My wife and I have had the opportunity to care for two (2) more girls; one aged 3 and the other aged 1. I wont go into the details of where we got them or how we got them, but they are here and its nice to see how they interact with our girls. Even so, my mind is racing with questions of what would happen if the girls stayed with us. How are we going to do lessons? How are we going to transport them? How are we going to do bed time and showers? Easy, you just take it one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Things that I noticed so far:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When little girls get together it seems to always be play time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My wife and I did our best to accommodate. We had to take both cars in order to get them to the park yesterday and it then use the baby bjorns to hold the little ones as we ran around chasing the more mobile of the two. It would have been more fun if we could have done it earlier in the day.
Baths arent that hard Bath time was done doing two by two and it wasnt that difficult, because Ive found that kids (or at least the ones Ive seen) like water. If anything it was difficult making them wait their turns and making sure they dont drown each other.
Dinner Well, its a good thing my wife and I have moved away from eating fast food and the like and actively plan and prepare meals in advance. It saves money (2 adults and 4 kids yikes!) and time (just heat and eat).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discipline&lt;/strong&gt; This was an awkward subject for me to handle. On one hand, Im a parent who is raising his daughters in a way I feel is right. On the other, these arent my children and I dont know what they are expecting. I dont spank, but I expect that what I say should be followed. So far, we havent had any big issues other than the older one pushing her sister down and a misunderstanding on what it means to share. Strangely enough, its my own daughter who's been giving us the most trouble. It could be because shes two now and wants to express herself with the word No or shes embolden now that we have company.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, I got my eye on her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bed Time&lt;/strong&gt;
This is actually, where things get a little more tricky. Thankfully, these girls sleep through the night, but it just begs the question of where do they sleep. We pretty much put the oldest one in my daughters crib, her sister has her own portable crib and our girls slept with mommy in the bed. Leaving me on the couch and I have to say its probably the best night of sleep that Ive had in days.
Well, that sums up the first day. The second one is today, and thankfully Im at work for most of it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="parenting"></category></entry><entry><title>My favorite new feature of facebook</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/01/my-favorite-new-feature-of-facebook.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-23T17:22:21-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-01-23:2010/01/my-favorite-new-feature-of-facebook.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I noticed something new in the email notifications that I get from facebook. They have allowed you to reply to a conversation without having to log into the website! This is awesome because you can follow along with a conversation without leaving your "productive" environment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Picture of an email in from a comment in facebook" src="facebook_mail.png" title="Picture of an email in from a comment in facebook" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="observation"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>Review (January 22nd, 2010)</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/01/review-january-22nd-2010.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-23T12:08:49-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-01-23:2010/01/review-january-22nd-2010.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, Ive been really ill. Maybe its all the stress that Ive been under: Looking for a new place to live, Asking for a raise, unresolved issues with my family, weird sleeping schedule (the kids), pressure to produce &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, heres a quick review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accomplishments:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asked for a raise (Which was quickly followed by questions of How do you do that special XYZ thing you do?) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep my head when I found out my account information was used to make some weird purchases &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a post to email-init to further information about email clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things on my mind:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a place to live &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on my personal relationships &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do a deeper review than this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically the same thing as last week&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="review"></category></entry><entry><title>Hacked!</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/01/hacked.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-23T11:39:38-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-01-23:2010/01/hacked.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, I got a notification that someone had stolen my account information to buy things online and that my account is going to be closed for the time being. It just goes to show that you have to be on top of this kind of stuff and people will take your money even if you dont have a lot in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, I just got the bill for the fixes to my doorway that was kicked in last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;$326!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must be out of your mind!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk about bad timing!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="money"></category><category term="security"></category></entry><entry><title>How I use Email</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/01/how-i-use-email.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-19T12:47:38-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-01-19:2010/01/how-i-use-email.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, Mac Developer Brent Simmons discussed on his &lt;a href="http://inessential.com/2010/01/16/email_init"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; about the importance of a good email client. Although, he said he wouldn't spearhead the project, he did start up a mailing list (ironic) for it. The list has been going crazy with people going back and forth over what the ideal mail client was and what should be in the 1.0 release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the posters, Matthieu Cormier, has posted on his &lt;a href="http://www.preenandprune.com/cocoamondo/?p=795"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; how he uses Mail.app and I thought it would be a good exercise to re-evaulate how I use mail and maybe that would help move the discussion along.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="A diagram of my mail usage" src="email.png" title="Diagram of my mail usage" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I made the switch from .mac to gmail and it's been kind of interesting to see how Mail.app handles mail. Before this point I was having gmail send all my email to my mac address and then using &lt;a href="http://www.indev.ca/MailActOn.html"&gt;Act-on&lt;/a&gt; to sort it into different folders. This worked alright when I was at home and had time to sort my email, unfortunately, I'm not always on my mac... and &lt;em&gt;sometimes&lt;/em&gt; .mac was down.
&lt;img alt="Screen of gmail" src="myEmail_work.png" title="Picture of gmail" /&gt;
Currently, I only use gmail and I've set up some labels and filters to manage it all. I have emails sent individually so that I can follow different threads quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I still enjoy working with a desktop client, if only for the sake of it flowing well with the rest of my "workflow" that includes working with omnifocus and a couple other tools that I like to use. If I can add one more issue against Mail.app that I haven't seen mentioned yet is that it doesn't allow you to color the heading on different threads.
&lt;img alt="Screen of mail.app" src="mail_screen.png" title="Picture of mail.app" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, thank you for your time!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category><category term="tech"></category><category term="email"></category></entry><entry><title>Peacoats and Money Diets</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/01/peacoats-and-money-diets.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-01-17:2010/01/peacoats-and-money-diets.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My wife and I took the kids to Costco today to load up on some of the necessities (namely toilet paper). As it is now fall, Costco has brought out some of their winter wear and my wife was a beautiful peacoat. My wife loves peacoats and has been saying that she would like something new because she's been loosing weight due to her new found passion for running. Like any husband I would love to get her the dress, but we have already bought her two other jackets in the last year plus a Scottevest that we got on sale two weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can't afford it. We haven't a need nor do we have any money in the budget for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife tries on a few and then sadly places the item back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's when my oldest daughter asks why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't even think about it and say, "We don't have the money to buy it."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instantly, my wife get's angry. Later on we talk about it briefly in the car and she tells me that I should have told our daughter about it in a different way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Should I have said, 'We can't afford it'?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"No, you should say it in a way so she won't misunderstand and get picked on."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I let the subject drop because I'm frustrated. As far as I'm concerned, I told my daughter exactly why we couldn't buy the coat in a way that shouldn't make anyone feel offended. I think it's one of the most important financial lessons an adult (or any one else for that matter) should know. You don't buy things if you can't afford them. If I had learned this lesson earlier or taken it to heart years ago, I'd be in a different financial situation. I don't want my daughters to go down that path an I certainly don't want them to think that they are less because they can't get everything they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's ok to know our limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But didn't I just say that I'm guilty of this as well?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, b-b-but...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;sigh&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've decided to place myself on a spending diet. I've already paid most of my bills for this month. I'm going to set aside $200 for gas and other expenses and place that in a my new Golden1 checking account and see how things go from there. I'm hoping that it helps me realize that the money my family needs to survive is different then the money I use for wantsies. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="money"></category><category term="parenting"></category></entry><entry><title>Review (January 15, 2010)</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/01/review-january-15-2010.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-15T20:46:34-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-01-15:2010/01/review-january-15-2010.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'd like to take this time to thank myself for not going completely crazy this last week. Crying babies, very little sleep and just the aftermath of all the drama from last month and I'm still standing...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...although a little wobbly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I'd like to take some time and do a little weekly review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal accomplishments this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish two projects for work that will reward the company for a while &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep my cool despite the constant pressure to find a new place and money to pay for it. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cut back on my liquid sugar intake. No soda! &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did a weekly review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things Still on my Mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to make more income &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to improve the relationship I have with my family &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are some more activities that I can do with my children in the winter time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="review"></category></entry><entry><title>The day after being sick</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/01/the-day-after-being-sick.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-12T17:02:54-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-01-12:2010/01/the-day-after-being-sick.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It just feels weird for a variety of reasons. There is the traditional protestant guilt that one is supposed to be working everyday combined with questioning wether or not you are contagious topped with the delicious pressure of all the things that need to be done. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yay!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="observation"></category></entry><entry><title>Pick yourself up and hit it again...</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/01/pick-yourself-up-and-hit-it-again.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-12T15:42:34-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-01-12:2010/01/pick-yourself-up-and-hit-it-again.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although you cant tell by only looking at my blog, but Ive made a commitment with myself to write more often. Its usually how I cope with some of the opportunities that life presents to me and I typically feel much better about myself and my path in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, Ive been having some difficulty getting started on some posts. I catch myself worrying more about what tool I'm going to use then the actual content of m writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was going to wonder what the pros use, but it doesn't matter. The important thing to do is to just write something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writers write. Programmer program. Simple.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>My father is coming home!</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/01/my-father-is-coming-home.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-05T23:11:21-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-01-05:2010/01/my-father-is-coming-home.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My father recently had a stroke and was doing some intense physical therapy down in Vallejo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But he's coming home today! This month is really coming around!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category></entry><entry><title>The Nightmare</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/01/the-nightmare.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-03T09:20:56-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-01-03:2010/01/the-nightmare.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, I woke up from a nightmare. I dreamed that I was unable to move forward with my life. That there was some list out there that kept track of my every mistake and that it prevented me from getting a raise at my current job or to move to another job. There was a guy who let me look at the list and it was filled with minute and cryptic offenses. The whole time I stood there shocked because there wasn't a way to defend myself... it was all on the paper that I wasn't supposed to see in the first place. What do I do? How can this be fair? Some of the things were so small as to seems inconsequential. Some of them had nothing to do with who I was, what I had done in the past or how I had changed over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waking up, I realized that I was looking at the fear I've of just letting my past mistakes dictate who I am and denying myself of the possibility of being better.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category><category term="dream"></category></entry><entry><title>Goals for the year</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/01/goals-for-the-year.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-02T20:45:37-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-01-02:2010/01/goals-for-the-year.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My goals for the year include (in no particular order)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get into great shape&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn and document a programming language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue to be a good father&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, let's see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="goals"></category><category term="personal"></category></entry></feed>