<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quotidian Quest</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2012-11-12T21:35:32-08:00</updated><entry><title>What am I going to do in this moment?</title><link href="/2012/11/what-am-i-going-to-do-in-this-moment.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-12T21:35:32-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:,2012-11-12:2012/11/what-am-i-going-to-do-in-this-moment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve thought about it. The desires of my life. About what I would I would do if I could do it in an instant. What would I do if I were to snap my fingers and the thing that I wanted were to magically happen; whether it was instantly get into shape or finish that book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is in these moments of clarity that I come closer to the reality that if I want to realize these hopes and dreams that I must first start towards them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A journey of a thousand miles began with a single step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, I’m not going to beat myself up about the steps I haven’t taken. There isn’t any point in doing that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to freak out about what tools to use or what direction to go in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to sit here, not afraid of what obstacles and hurdles I may run into or worry that I’m going the wrong way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to take this moment and be thankful for the opportunities that I have in front of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m alive and in good health. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a family downstairs reading to each other and living in the moment created by the universe just for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finish this little piece of writing, I’m going down to be with them knowing that although I have millions and millions of possibilities for things to do, I only have so many moments to be with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is a kind of peace of mind that money or dreams can’t buy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="observation"></category></entry><entry><title>Another day</title><link href="/2011/02/another-day.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-02-06T10:11:12-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:,2011-02-06:2011/02/another-day.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, World.&lt;br /&gt;
I'm alive for another year. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>