<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quotidian Quest</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/feeds/productivity.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://quotidianquest.com/</id><updated>2012-07-02T20:12:03-07:00</updated><entry><title>Considering my task managment</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/07/considering-my-task-managment.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-02T20:12:03-07:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-07-02:2012/07/considering-my-task-managment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A while ago I came across some questions to consider everytime that I do a review of my tasks. The problem is that I've attached the questions to a task in OmniFocus and -honestly- I don't think it's helpful to do something like that unless I think and write about it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this system trustworthy? If not, why not? Do I need to make better backups?&lt;br /&gt;
No, there are two major problems with the personal productivity. The first is that I don't schedule enough time for something. How can I finish a task when I don't make any time for it. Secondly, I don't do enough positive reviews. I need to do a review every day to make sure that tasks don't fall through the cracks and I don't overwhelm myself. I find most of my reviews are when I'm under the gun. Not a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there a next actionable task? Can it actually be readily done?&lt;br /&gt;
Yes... for the most part. I have a couple projects that have items like "Brainstorm next action".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When do I anticipate looking at this next action’s context?&lt;br /&gt;
This goes back to the first question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will this project look like when it is done?
Depends on the project, baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When do I think I’ll need to see this project again?&lt;br /&gt;
That also depends on the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="goals"></category><category term="productivity"></category></entry><entry><title>A short review of GTD and Me</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2012/03/a-short-review-of-gtd-and-me.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-04T21:23:51-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2012-03-04:2012/03/a-short-review-of-gtd-and-me.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I first heard about GTD around 2005, I had just finished school and found myself wondering what I was going to do with my life. I was living paycheck to paycheck not because of financial hardship but because I couldn't imagine life outside of the current moment. For me, GTD was blessing because it got thoughts off my mind and put them on a list somewhere...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem at that the time that my list was definitely not a trusted system and I found myself looking for more and more productivity porn to help manage my prioritize. All of this just amounted to me just moving things around on my plate and it certainly did not get me started on the oh so important habit of reviewing what I put on to the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that the underlining reason I didn't work for me was that I was avoiding a task that every adult needs to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grow up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn't on the list exactly, but in a way accomplishing things on the list would symbolize that I was leaving the "carefree" world of "come what may" for the complicated world of "come this time next month I should do A though O".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was hard, but I've grown and I look forward to taking responsibility and the list has turned into lists with different meanings and I understand the real importance of what GTD does. It heps you realize what is important to you so that you can have an idea of what you shoud be doing and in that find out who you are.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="GTD"></category></entry><entry><title>43 Folders | Time, Attention, and Creative Work</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/02/43-folders-time-attention-and-creative-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-04T15:11:45-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-02-04:2010/02/43-folders-time-attention-and-creative-work.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="What happens if you check your email every 5 minutes" src="24000.jpg" title="You waste soooo much time" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, I can't believe I spent so much time looking into productivity p0rn! I used to look at 43folders.com almost every other hour looking for that "One secret that would make me productive".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secret, just do it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="productivity"></category><category term="email"></category></entry><entry><title>How I use Email</title><link href="http://quotidianquest.com/2010/01/how-i-use-email.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-19T12:47:38-08:00</updated><author><name>Mandaris</name></author><id>tag:quotidianquest.com,2010-01-19:2010/01/how-i-use-email.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, Mac Developer Brent Simmons discussed on his &lt;a href="http://inessential.com/2010/01/16/email_init"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; about the importance of a good email client. Although, he said he wouldn't spearhead the project, he did start up a mailing list (ironic) for it. The list has been going crazy with people going back and forth over what the ideal mail client was and what should be in the 1.0 release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the posters, Matthieu Cormier, has posted on his &lt;a href="http://www.preenandprune.com/cocoamondo/?p=795"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; how he uses Mail.app and I thought it would be a good exercise to re-evaulate how I use mail and maybe that would help move the discussion along.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="A diagram of my mail usage" src="email.png" title="Diagram of my mail usage" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I made the switch from .mac to gmail and it's been kind of interesting to see how Mail.app handles mail. Before this point I was having gmail send all my email to my mac address and then using &lt;a href="http://www.indev.ca/MailActOn.html"&gt;Act-on&lt;/a&gt; to sort it into different folders. This worked alright when I was at home and had time to sort my email, unfortunately, I'm not always on my mac... and &lt;em&gt;sometimes&lt;/em&gt; .mac was down.
&lt;img alt="Screen of gmail" src="myEmail_work.png" title="Picture of gmail" /&gt;
Currently, I only use gmail and I've set up some labels and filters to manage it all. I have emails sent individually so that I can follow different threads quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I still enjoy working with a desktop client, if only for the sake of it flowing well with the rest of my "workflow" that includes working with omnifocus and a couple other tools that I like to use. If I can add one more issue against Mail.app that I haven't seen mentioned yet is that it doesn't allow you to color the heading on different threads.
&lt;img alt="Screen of mail.app" src="mail_screen.png" title="Picture of mail.app" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, thank you for your time!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category><category term="tech"></category><category term="email"></category></entry></feed>